<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Banks on Monax Industries</title>
    <link>http://localhost/tags/banks/</link>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost/tags/banks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What Bankers Could Learn From the Open Source Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/02/03/on-open-source-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/02/03/on-open-source-banks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/opensourceway/8297629214/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/open_source.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot over the course of 2015. One of the things which has been interesting is my own move from working with nearly &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; free and open source folks to working with many incumbent firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the openData and legalHacker lands in which I spent much of 2013-2014 things are very different than in a modern, multinational corporation. The approaches of these groups of humans to how they build and use software is markedly different. Of course there are many differences, yet in this think piece, I&amp;rsquo;d like to tease out one of those differences &amp;ndash; how they approach open source software &amp;ndash; that I&amp;rsquo;ve observed during my journey. Hopefully with a mind to communicating some of my own thoughts to the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;but-first-what-s-open-source-about-at-least-in-my-opinion&#34;&gt;But first, what&amp;rsquo;s open source &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo;, at least in my opinion?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a range of arguments seeking to answer the question: &lt;em&gt;why do big tech firms participate in open source software&lt;/em&gt;? The most obvious argument of course is that the folks who write software for a living would have an ability to share the costs of the development of some of that software with other firms where they did not have a differentiated problem set nor did they have differentiated corporate interests. There are other arguments of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the union of non-differentiated problem sets and non-diffentiated corporate interests is, in my opinion, the driver towards more corporates using open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a range of arguments seeking to answer the question: &lt;em&gt;why are goverments completely misguided if they are not participating in open source software&lt;/em&gt;? In the governance regime vendor lock in is slowly, but surely, becoming a bad thing thereby giving an edge to open source software. There has been a ton of thought leadership, groundbreaking collaborations, and other very fascinating work that has come out of the civic hacker and open data worlds. Much of this was enabled by and sought to give back to a range of open source software. The best folks within these movements understand that open source software is a two way street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good to &lt;code&gt;consume&lt;/code&gt; open source software; even better to &lt;code&gt;participate&lt;/code&gt; in open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are a range of arguments seeking to answer the question: &lt;em&gt;why is the legal community increasingly participating in open source software&lt;/em&gt;? While in many ways the openLaw, legalHacker, and legalTech movements have somewhat differing pathways, they all rely heavily on open source software. And, they all know that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By participating in an ecosystem one can catalyze something with a greater reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to answer the originally posed question, my own opinion about open source software lies at the intersection of those three vectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namely, to me open source is about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allocating individualized resources towards a collective effort to solve a common problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participating in the community, dialogue, effort for the &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; on which one&amp;rsquo;s own competitive advantage is built&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greatly increased reach of thoughts, opinions, strategy, and&amp;hellip; code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-can-this-apply-to-bankers&#34;&gt;How can this apply to bankers?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;rsquo;d say there are three big lessons which bankers can learn from the open source community. One last caveat is that in this post I&amp;rsquo;m not talking to bank IT-ers. They already use a ton of open source software (although maybe management could actually let them send pull requests a bit easier :-) ). This post was written with the folks on the business side in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-1-think-about-your-ecosystem-rather-than-only-on-one-cell-s-walls&#34;&gt;Lesson 1: Think About Your Ecosystem Rather than Only On One Cell&amp;rsquo;s Walls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the grand scheme of things a company&amp;rsquo;s firewall is less like the great wall of china than it is like the outer walls of our cells. Meaning, they&amp;rsquo;re semi-permeable and move around a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cell&amp;rsquo;s walls are, well, a pretty important thing. We would not be alive without them. And a company&amp;rsquo;s firewalls (which I&amp;rsquo;m using generically to mean the company&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;safe computing zone&amp;rdquo;) are equally important. The modern world would likely not be where it is without them. Yet if we put too much emphasis on a single cell&amp;rsquo;s walls are we not missing the bigger picture?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bank, its customers, its products, its platform, its employees, they all shape and formulate &amp;ldquo;what a bank is&amp;rdquo;. They each know folks who work at other banks and who face very similar problem sets. Indeed there are many problem sets that fall into the category of: everyone in town agrees that X is a common problem and, also, we evoke no competitive advantage in how we individually address that problem. In tech that will often lead to a &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s collaborate here&amp;rdquo; discussion. And, increasingly, bankers are, at least theoretically, &amp;ldquo;buying into&amp;rdquo; this &amp;ldquo;idea&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationships that are gained by the interactions that take place &amp;ldquo;outside the cell&amp;rsquo;s walls&amp;rdquo; are vital to modern, functional economies. And banks need to embrace this quickly or they will be replaced quickly with those that do understand this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to what the blockers are, it seems to me at least that the blockers are mainly bad processes at the cell&amp;rsquo;s walls. Every bank&amp;rsquo;s IT rules are different, but in general they slow down communication which could be mutually valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the best strategies for corporates trying to engage more in open source are to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have clear boundaries around what is proprietary work and what is open source work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do not have a 100:0 ratio between the above (what is proprietary and what is open source)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;communicate those boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have policies in place for when folks may think &amp;ldquo;i&amp;rsquo;m not sure&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is purely subjective, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-2-think-like-a-participant-not-a-consumer&#34;&gt;Lesson 2: Think Like a Participant, Not a Consumer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson is quite personal to me. And it has been a part of my own journey getting to know bankers and insurance folks and many others who were outside previous orbits I had spun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days I realized that many bankers have a habit to say: &lt;em&gt;sell me a solution to a problem I have&lt;/em&gt;. In banking this is no different than what many in government say. Moving to consuming open source software is one thing, but it is only an important first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one starts &lt;code&gt;participating&lt;/code&gt; in open source software, one truly sees its benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In actuality one moves from the maker-user relationship being &amp;ldquo;we ask, you deliver&amp;rdquo; (or not), to a relationship of &amp;ldquo;hey we did this cool thing that was helpful for both of us and lots of other folks like it so it is much easier to maintain than if we did it purely internally&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take two otherwise equal skill level developers. Let&amp;rsquo;s say one works at a global bank. And the other one works in a tech company. They are both working with an open source piece of software. They both find a bug in that software. What happens now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer in Tech Company&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; goes to github.com (since they&amp;rsquo;re statistically most likely to be working from there) and files a bug report, watches the bug as it is responded to by the project and helps to debug the problem along the way if necessary, and when the bug is fixed generally says &amp;ldquo;thanks folks&amp;rdquo; and merges it into whatever he was blocked on by the bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer in Bank&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; calls someone? their open source solutions provider? emails someone? reports it to internal ticketing system? And then asks how does the bugfix get back into my stuff?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because, and this is a gross generalization, tech companies have adopted ecosystems thinking a bit faster than banks, tech companies have crafted their policies to include the idea that, yeah, developers may go to github and use their &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; account, because they have seen and felt the value in thinking beyond only the cell walls of their individual company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-3-the-bank-as-a-platform-idea-is-happening-get-global-scale&#34;&gt;Lesson 3: The Bank as a Platform Idea is Happening, Get Global Scale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love watching our analytics. It is wonderful to see folks from all around the world, around the clock, understanding a bit more about the &lt;code&gt;way of the marmot&lt;/code&gt;. If we &amp;ldquo;sold&amp;rdquo; Eris, rather than what we do do, which is selling components of applications that just so happen to run well on Eris, then we would have to build a much bigger sales force than we have. In other words, and blockchain startups I&amp;rsquo;m gonna let you in on a little secret here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to do strategic pre-selling of your product is to be open source by default and closed source only where necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a banker wants to try eris today to build their own little tiny blockchain backed application &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.erisindustries.com/tutorials/getting-started/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;it should take them about 2 hours with no technical background&lt;/a&gt;. And that banker could be in Hargeisa, Somaliland (where I know it&amp;rsquo;s happened). Or New York (where I know it&amp;rsquo;s happened). Or anywhere (not sure it&amp;rsquo;s happened there). Instantly, tons of bankers can &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; what this stuff &amp;ldquo;feels&amp;rdquo; like, how the &amp;ldquo;engine&amp;rdquo; runs, etc. in a pretty approachable manner. All without us at Eris having to do any more than we would do even if we weren&amp;rsquo;t open source by default: namely code, test, and document our tooling. In some ways we do &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; because we are an open source by default company because our users help us to debug the challenges they face and refine how we communicate &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a future which I&amp;rsquo;d say is definitely in the range of the possible. Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine that multiple firms jostle for competitive advantage around &amp;ldquo;plugging fiat&amp;rdquo; into &amp;ldquo;chains&amp;rdquo;. And let&amp;rsquo;s also imagine that we are in a land where the plurality of chains folks have been &amp;gt;= 20% correct (in other words we have lots of chains, configured in lots of ways, doing lots of things, for lots of reasons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For firms to compete here they would need to tackle two distinct challenges. One of which is how to make it so the chains (with or without various business logic layers of abstraction) plug into your service/offering/platform/thing. The other of which is how do you plug your service/offering/platform/thing into a global or regional payments network (which may or may not be cryptocurrency based; a topic to which I&amp;rsquo;m decidedly agnostic)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A neat problem to tackle for sure. And the firms that win that game will need to achieve global scale. And to do so, they&amp;rsquo;re likely gonna have to open source some things. Perhaps that is a suite of payment instructions smart contracts with various types and levels of permissions so that the firm can move money around IRL based on what a bunch of different chains are sending. Perhaps it is parsing UTXO&amp;rsquo;s so that the firm can move money around IRL based on what a bunch of different chains are sending. (Most likely it will be both.) Then, if a new startup wanted to use this firm &amp;ldquo;to move money around for them&amp;rdquo;, whether that was the hot new real estate application, or the wizkids with the machine learning algo and a desire to lower credit risk for smaller companies, all they&amp;rsquo;d need to do is to import a library of smart contracts and be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of the above is not the details, it was simply an example. That said, I do think we&amp;rsquo;re going to get there faster than many folks realize. The point of the above is to show how a bank that took the &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re a tech company first&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re a platform first&amp;rdquo; approach to business could be working internally to open doors for their folks to be able to participate in open source (which is much more than &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rsquo;s our API&amp;rdquo;). Because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation in open source is the easiest way to rapidly achieve global scale in an information age economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no easy answers here. But I do think that banks would be wise to at a minimum begin to address the fairly clear areas in Lesson 1. Banks are increasingly consumers of open source software and many developers within banks are excited by the idea of being able to work more collaboratively and participatorial-y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/opensourceway/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Photo credit: CC-BY-SA: OpenSource.com @ Flickr )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now. A few quotes that helped refine my thinking about Eris and our open source by default strategy to software design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re asking the wrong question. Open source is in part a) A license b) A methodology for developing something and c) A community of interested people. Feel free to add more items. But notice… open source is not a business model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source can help you reduce your expenses. This can be from sharing costs and risks for R&amp;amp;D. There’s other interesting benefits such as faster time to market potentially as well. You may see benefits from marketing if people are trying your software before they buy. If you can really do it well, you can open up a whole new market with open source components and a consortium of complementary partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://42aross.wordpress.com/2012/07/20/just-how-do-you-make-money-with-open-source/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at Linux Foundation sponsored events not only helps us with our open source visibility, but provides a great way for us to find potential candidates for our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that you could be the best coder on the block, and that was enough. In some projects, that might still be the case, but to effectively balance a community&amp;rsquo;s needs with a corporation&amp;rsquo;s wants, you have to be able to code/design well, and also articulate ideas and sell them to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://opensource.com/business/14/10/interview-Guy-Martin-Samsung&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideology isn&amp;rsquo;t what has sold the open source model. It started gaining attention when it was obvious that open source was the best method of developing and improving the highest quality technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Linus Torvalds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adoption of open source code allows businesses to harness the creativity and labour of both their employees and their customers in a way that is not available to firms employing only proprietary software licenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the possibility of a shortened development time (e.g., Dahlander, 2007), open source projects commonly report a wider adoption of their code (e.g., West, 2003) and receive more high-quality feedback and bug reports than closed source projects (see Schindler [2007] for a comparison). Open source licensing also enables a faster average time from discovery to solution (Schindler, 2007). Indeed, open source products have been often shown to be superior to their proprietary counterparts (e.g., Wheeler, 2007). Furthermore, companies can see development of their product in directions they did not realize was significant to their users, as well as the development of features that are too far from the firm’s core business to receive in-house funding for development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://timreview.ca/article/756&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological motivations include the advantages of levering the intelligence of collectives, obtaining code that is not available in proprietary software, and the quality and reliability of OSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://timreview.ca/article/635&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchains and Banks, or Why Hearn&#39;s Post Isn&#39;t a PR Stunt</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/01/17/blockchains-and-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/01/17/blockchains-and-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jakerust/16826216252/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/banks-blockchains.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a subjective piece full of selection bias and my own experiences. Take it for what it is worth: one human&amp;rsquo;s experiences and opinions. It is no more, nor less, than that.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s also quite inside baseball for many who are not entrenched in the blockchains space. If you find yourself reading this and do not know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, then this post probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t written with you in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Hearn recently wrote a piece which has the bitcoin and blockchain communities all aflutter. For different reasons. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about then please see above (tl;dr, this post probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t written with you in mind).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I have seen those who identify themselves as capital &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; Bitcoiners have negatively reacted to Mike&amp;rsquo;s post in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;good riddance&lt;/code&gt; you jerk. never liked you anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bitcoin can&#39;t die&lt;/code&gt; you jerk. &lt;sticks head back in sand&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;banks are behind this&lt;/code&gt; you jerk. I see what you&amp;rsquo;re up to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to the first, I personally think it is shameful of many in the bitcoin community to discount Mike&amp;rsquo;s many contributions to the bitcoin ecosystem over the years simply because he wrote a piece breaking up with bitcoin. Sure it was a very public breakup, but Mike&amp;rsquo;s a passionate, opinionated, driven guy. Everyone can see that. Did anyone expect differently no matter whether he and bitcoin stayed together, stayed friends with benefits, or broke up? I followed it on both /r/bitcoin and on /r/btc. The difference between the responses was staggering. If one wants to see the humanly decent parts of the bitcoin community, I would encourage them &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to look at one of those two subreddits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to the second, bitcoin has issues. These are issues because bitcoin as both one blockchain and as some applications atop it (the bitcoin currency, among others such as ascribe, open bazaar, etc.) are reaching the thresholds of what its base blockchain can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;! Exciting! Good news. On the other hand, the system&amp;rsquo;s gotta upgrade. Somehow, someway. And soon. As with all collective decision making processes, it won&amp;rsquo;t be easy. After doing governance reform for years and working on political decentralization for nearly a decade I can say, though, that Andreas, respectfully, I have &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; seen this actually work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Bitcoin&amp;#39;s invention was an engineering solution to a governance problem. We can solve bitcoin&amp;#39;s governance challenges with more engineering&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; AndreasMAntonopoulos (@aantonop) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aantonop/status/688111075389120518&#34;&gt;January 15, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ve seen that sentiment &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt; times. Collective decision making was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/project-douglas/eris&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;first big problem&lt;/a&gt; which hooked me on this technology. It is a hard, hard problem. And it is &lt;em&gt;only partially&lt;/em&gt; an engineering problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to the third, well the rest of this post is about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dionyziz/d0372c3a633a7784fb91&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@dionyziz, wrote an interesting post&lt;/a&gt;. It was one of the most level pieces I&amp;rsquo;ve read and does not really fall into any of the big traps listed above. Indeed, after I read it I was going to leave a comment with a shorter version of this post, but instead of &amp;ldquo;polluting&amp;rdquo; his voice with my own, I decided to post here. Also I had more thoughts than I originally guessed I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the piece @dionyziz writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His involvement in the bitcoin community was huge and I think we should all appreciate what he did without dismissing his work as many tend to do now that he&amp;rsquo;s distancing himself from the project. Despite the fun googler bitcoin meetups we&amp;rsquo;ve had with Mike in Zürich, I want to make sure everyone is aware of his current involvement with 30 large centralized banks including ING, Goldman Sachs, Bank of America, and JP Morgan through his key professional position at R3. It is clear that there is conflict of interest between his blockchain work with these banks, where decentralization is undesired, and the democratized blockchain for the people in modern cryptocurrencies. His blogs and publications must be read critically and keeping this in mind, even if he denies conflict of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with the final sentence and believe that &lt;em&gt;everyone&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; blogs and publications should be read critically and with the author&amp;rsquo;s biases in mind. Including my own. Now to my real critique of the quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that I seriously doubt a single member of the bitcoin community does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; know that Mike works for R3, of course it is fine to point it out. Albeit, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; want to make sure everyone is aware that R3&amp;rsquo;s involvement is with &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; than 30 large banks. Indeed, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coindesk.com/twelve-banks-blockchain-consortium-r3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IIRC the number is 42&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start there with that number. 42. 42 of the largest, most powerful, most driven, most competitive organizations on earth. Each individual bank may or may not care about decentralization, but if R3 is going to effectively navigate the waters they are embarking upon, R3 better understand peer-to-peer communication systems, distributed governance &amp;amp; rulemaking, as well as p2p incentive mechanisms. If they do not they will be unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is a harder challenge? Wrangling 42 of the most competitive organizations in the world to collaborate on a product you hope to be in the business of selling them for the foreseeable future, or being a bitcoin core developer and accountable to&amp;hellip;? Three or four mining pools and four or five wallets/exchanges? And being accountable how&amp;hellip;? Twitter and Reddit aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly known for providing accountability mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to the part of the quote which led to this post. The normative statement &lt;code&gt;It is clear that there is conflict of interest between his blockchain work with these banks, where decentralization is undesired&lt;/code&gt;. This is an assumption. The author very obviously does not speak for the individuals who work at banks, nor for their boards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience that statement is not only an assumption, it is patently untrue. I say this based on Eris&amp;rsquo; working with many of the same banks as R3 and many of the same bankers (albeit at different levels). Read Alex Batlin&amp;rsquo;s work (which is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alexbatlin/status/589062280152743936&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; ). Read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sytaylor.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Simon Taylor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s work. To name a few that are mentally handy. Many within banks who are leading the experiments with this technology do not take the perspective that &lt;code&gt;decentralization is undesired&lt;/code&gt;. That is a normative judgment, and an assumption, made from afar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks are large, complex organizations. As I have argued in the past, a modern bank is much more decentralized than a small business is. Indeed I would argue that Brian Armstrong likely has much more &amp;ldquo;centralized&amp;rdquo; control over what Coinbase does than Brian Moynihan has over what BoA does. Do we claim that Coinbase does not desire decentralization because Brian Armstrong centralizes some decision making in himself as the CEO of his company? If not then I do not see why the counterargument does not hold. At least if we&amp;rsquo;re being intellectually honest and not just &amp;ldquo;hating on bankers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all that aside, let&amp;rsquo;s look at what banks are &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; doing with this technology rather than what we &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they&amp;rsquo;re doing with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What banks are doing, today, with blockchain technology is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gendal/status/688434789855145985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;orthogonal&lt;/a&gt; (at best), &lt;a href=&#34;https://erisindustries.com/use_cases/bankers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;completely different&lt;/a&gt; (at worst) to what decentralized cryptocurrencies are trying to achieve. Banks do not necessarily view the technology as a technical backbone for a new monetary ecosystem. Some do. At least until their risk and compliance departments get involved. But this technology, when viewed as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.erisindustries.com/explainers/smart_contracts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;business process improvement software which cuts across stakeholders&lt;/a&gt;, has little to nothing to do with money on the internet. Why? Three big reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cryptocurrencies solve a problem that some users some of the time have, but banks themselves don&amp;rsquo;t have a payments problem and the user base of all of crytocurrency is a drop in the ocean for a large, traditional bank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compliance with regulation is a challenge for bitcoin companies, who have a political belief in the technology. Without that religio-political bias and without a sufficient user base, it likely isn&amp;rsquo;t worth a bank&amp;rsquo;s time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;even if a bank used a cryptocurrency backend, even a public one, its core functions of providing financial services would largely remain unchanged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it utterly amusing that folks who have been around the world of bitcoin think that the banks are working on an &amp;ldquo;altCoin&amp;rdquo; which will somehow compete with bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck banks in developing your bankCoin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say smugly to themselves on Twitter and Reddit to a stream of retweets and upvotes. In response I smile and think of the above. Banks don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a &amp;ldquo;coin&amp;rdquo; whether it&amp;rsquo;s bitcoin or JPMorganCoin or R3Coin. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; anything for them. Sure, many banks are exploring &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.erisindustries.com/explainers/contracts_v_tokens/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tokenized solutions around specific domains&lt;/a&gt;, but this has absolutely nothing to do with currency. Large traditional banks make very little money via currency itself and much more money around creating, trading, administering, and servicing complex financial assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If what a bank is doing with blockchain technology competes with a public blockchain ecosystem (and I do not think it does) it is much more likely to be competing with ethereum&amp;rsquo;s than it is bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s. Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s network simply does not have the complex logic which is required to provide the step change necessary for systems to be taken to production. And before the responses come in about &amp;ldquo;well this will be fixed by&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; a magic wand? I will be quick to respond that if the block size &amp;ldquo;debate&amp;rdquo; is any indication of bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s ability to upgrade itself I do not hold hope for massive improvements in its VM any time soon. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/compleatang/status/685342421429927936&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shameless plug, the Eris blockchain application platform runs all these blockchains just fine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s move to the second bullet point. Should the regulatory environment change with respect to cryptocurrencies, and should cryptocurrencies continue to gain adoption, I would not be surprised if some bankers open up services around cryptocurrencies. Let us imagine that world for a second. And if some get their druthers it is a world which will happen. Let us then ask ourselves what would be the difference between &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fidorbank.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fidor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coinbase.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt; in such a world? Would they provide differentiated services? I will go on the record and say that in such a world they are much more likely to be direct competitors of one another than not. Why? Well, that brings us to the third bullet point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies, even if we accept the &amp;ldquo;be your own bank line&amp;rdquo;, do not do away with the need for &lt;em&gt;financial services&lt;/em&gt; that banks routinely provide. This is a very important point and one that is under talked about. And both challenger banks and large bitcoin companies will converge around providing consumer facing financial services for millennials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;As (I think) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nivertech&#34;&gt;@nivertech&lt;/a&gt; first said: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/reintermediation?src=hash&#34;&gt;#reintermediation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/3Qfcd2TbaC&#34;&gt;https://t.co/3Qfcd2TbaC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Casey Kuhlman (@compleatang) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/compleatang/status/678180902955036672&#34;&gt;December 19, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one looks closely at, and abstracts the methodology of delivering, the service suite being provided by the large bitcoin companies and the small challenger banks, one would have a hard time finding the points of differentiation. Save for the fact that one goes all in on a decentralized cryptocurrency of course &amp;ndash; which ultimately is simply a methodology of delivering services. In other words, I think it&amp;rsquo;s safe to say that as Coinbase continues to grow vis a vis the number of downloads of bitcoin-qt that we are moving into a world of #reintermediation not #disintermediation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are two independent vectors here. On the one hand, what traditional banks are doing with this technology is not about moving tokens of endogenous value between nodes on a network. On the other hand, large bitcoin companies are looking more and more like small banks by the day. This gets us to my final point of response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a massive difference between a traditional bank and a challenger bank. Not only in customer base, but also in business mix. Challenger banks are largely focused on winning the consumer markets. This is what, in the bank world, is called a retail bank. Traditional, large banks, sure they have consumer accounts, but that is not where they make most of their money. They make money by providing financial services (which is &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt; more than simply moving currencies around) to large corporations. Within a traditional large bank, providing consumer facing depository services is simply a loss leader. Of course it is fair to critique that, but if one wants to critique it one should come at the critique from a point of knowledge rather than a point of ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point here, I guess, is that if the bitcoin community feels it has competition from the banking sector, that competition is coming from challenger banks, not the large traditional banks the community so loves to &amp;ldquo;hate on&amp;rdquo;. Perhaps instead of wringing its hands about what JP Morgan does with blockchain it should worry about what Fidor is doing (:heart: Fidor, by the way, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.anthemis.com/our-portfolio/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a fellow Anthemis&lt;/a&gt; portfolio company).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some will argue, well, if we move to a world where cryptocurrencies dominate over fiat currencies then the banks can&amp;rsquo;t do what they&amp;rsquo;re currently doing around money creation and fractional reserve banking. And I would call that person a partial ignoramus. Look at the many bitcoin exchange failure who admitted in public that they did do fractional reserve &amp;ldquo;banking&amp;rdquo;. And that&amp;rsquo;s simply what we know of. It is not only possible, it has happened. Repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money creation, indeed is a point of difference between fiat and cryptocurrencies. But I fail to find a consensus within economics which says this is a normative good or a normative bad. There is certainly consensus within some individual schools of economic thought; particularly within those lauded by crytocurrency advocates. But within the fuller spectrum of economics I do not find a consensus that it would be better for economies if the money creation process were algorithmic rather than federated. Or, as David Galbraith put it more succintly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Bitcoin: standards central; creation distributed; processing monopoly. Fiat: standards central; creation franchised; processing distributed&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; David Galbraith (@daveg) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/daveg/status/687949541082017792&#34;&gt;January 15, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central point of this piece is basically to say this. Calm down bitcoin. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be alright. No single banker I&amp;rsquo;ve met, and I&amp;rsquo;ve met and work with plenty, has ever said to me that they were in competition with bitcoin. Indeed, most find this idea laughable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have much bigger, more immediate problems to solve. Problems which the raw blockchain and smart contract technology is better suited to help them with than any one application built on the technological core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And. Now. For some be happy music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UQ48Oj4ZNvA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jakerust/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Photo credit: CC-BY: www.gotcredit.com )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>