<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcements on Monax Industries</title>
    <link>http://localhost/categories/announcements/</link>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost/categories/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marmot Den - Our Community Slack - is Open For Business!</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/08/08/the-marmot-den-open-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/08/08/the-marmot-den-open-for-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the launch of our new &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.eris.industries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Slack Community - The Marmot Den&lt;/a&gt;, allowing anyone to easily sign-up and access various discussion/support channels. This decision comes after the realization that the Slack experience we were offering to our users was lackluster. The migration is about providing a harmonized user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we provide both an irc channel (freenode: #erisindustries) and a support e-mail, often the easiest way for users to get - and us to provide - support, was in one of several semi-public Slack channels. Once in our Slack, most users were confined to #community-vip. Some power-users eventually made their way into tool/topic specific channels, though as one user pointed out &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of bot activity in here that&amp;rsquo;s useful to devs but not necessarily users, where can I go for updates?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In three words: &lt;strong&gt;too much friction&lt;/strong&gt;. These channels were noisy and hard to get to. And the whole process was manual; individual invitations were required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.eris.industries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Marmot Den is open&lt;/a&gt; to anyone and trims all irrelevant notifications for the various tools that make up our platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome you in to: ask a question, report a bug, request a feature, talk tooling, brainstorm your smart contract backed distributed application, or any other blockchain topic that one may fancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing you &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.eris.industries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in The Den&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eris Industries supports the EEA Option</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/06/27/eea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/06/27/eea/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Being a lawyer-led company, Eris Industries has a bunch of legal knowledge in-house - more so than most software companies. As such, we&amp;rsquo;re quick to form opinions about policy matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/jan/13/david-cameron-encrypted-messaging-apps-ban&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;very early opposition&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/2015/11/02/IPBill/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#IPBill&lt;/a&gt; eighteen months ago to our pro-remain position on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/02/16/getin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#Brexit&lt;/a&gt;, we take public positions on policy matters early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally we have thoughts on the EU membership referendum which occurred last week. You may have noticed that the people of the United Kingdom voted &amp;ldquo;Leave.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-tremendous-disappointment-for-british-business&#34;&gt;A tremendous disappointment for British business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any way you look at the &amp;ldquo;Leave&amp;rdquo; vote, it is a huge disappointment for British business. Two years ago, Eris Industries had three employees who worked out of our homes. Today, we have 17, with our head office remaining for the moment in London, an office in Berlin, and a subsidiary operating from New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are Europeans. Our team is French, Italian, Belgian, German, Swiss, English and Scottish. (American, Canadian, and South African, too.) We simply could not have assembled this team, and grown as we have, without the UK being a member of the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect wailing and gnashing of teeth on this issue across London and the UK over the coming weeks and months. Because the British people chose this outcome, denial is not productive. Nor is it a choice. As democrats we must accept that we are dealing with an exit from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we can mitigate. British and global companies can, and should, start considering our options and work towards adopting a common position. In Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; view, far and away the best option on the table is what the Adam Smith Institute calls the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamsmith.org/blog/time-for-the-eea-option&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EEA Option&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-we-support-the-eeaoption&#34;&gt;Why we support the #EEAOption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EEA option de-risks Brexit. It allows British business to thrive, and allows European and global business to deal with the whole of Europe - and the wider world - from their current bases in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are very sound business reasons to support this positon. As an information-age startup with a distributed workforce, when we started up in the UK, the UK&amp;rsquo;s membership of the single market made it easy for us to expand our operations on the continent with very little hassle. It&amp;rsquo;s always hard to find the right people. However, being able to hire in Germany, Belgium, and elsewhere meant we always managed to get our hands on the right candidates to help our business grow and expand into the world-leading blockchain technology provider we are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We and our employees benefit from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.polipedia.eu/tiki-index.php?page=Four+Freedoms+of+the+European+Union&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the four freedoms&lt;/a&gt;, especially those of free movement of labour and capital. If these freedoms are taken away, new, innovative businesses that follow in our footsteps will be hamstrung by stricter immigration restrictions, tax regulations, and compliance obligations, as well as reduced availability of investor funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom of movement is really the most critical piece. With it we can hire the best people Europe has to offer, and deploy them where we need them, when we need them, for as long as we need them to be there. Without it, our compliance costs would go up and we simply wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to get the right talent - because there simply isn&amp;rsquo;t enough of it concentrated in any one place in the European Economic Area. This includes London, which (as anyone in tech will tell you) is simply not the hub of global tech talent it fancies itself to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you see, Brexiteers, freedom of movement is not merely about holidays in the south of France or a shorter queue at the UK border. To be blunt, &lt;strong&gt;without freedom of movement in the EU/EEA, British firms cannot compete effectively in global markets.&lt;/strong&gt; The UK&amp;rsquo;s talent pool has proven far too small for our requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our conclusion is that the only compromise option that ticks the boxes in terms of business’ interests – from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;free movement of labour, to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the single passport for financial services, to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tariff-free trade with the EU,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which is also palatable from the perspective of the Brexiters and the much-beloved Scots, is the EEA Option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-others-should-support-the-eea-option&#34;&gt;Why others should support the EEA Option&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We therefore support the EEA Option &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamsmith.org/evolution-not-revolution&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(full paper here)&lt;/a&gt;, emphatically. We would encourage others to do the same, for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boris Johnson, Daniel Hannan, and Douglas Carswell – all free marketeers, each of whom are likely to have some say in what the outcome of the Brexit discussions are – have all hinted (or, in Carswell and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/eu-referendum-tory-campaigner-admits-brexit-immigration-some-control-a7102626.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hannan’s case&lt;/a&gt;, expressly stated) that continued membership in the single market is desirable. This is an entirely sensible and prudent position to hold and is in the interests of British business. We should let them know we support this position, which will substantially mitigate the damage of Brexit to British business, as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 48-52 defeat is not a mandate to withdraw from all trade relations with the EU and “go it alone” – the so-called “WTO Option” – but rather it is only a mandate to leave the EU. We owe it to the majority to leave, but they owe it to the (very large) minority to concede some middle ground. Compromise is hard, but needed, considering &lt;strong&gt;any exit will operate to unilaterally strip 16 million (!) British citizens, and British businesses, of EU citizenship and the rights and freedoms we currently enjoy and do not wish to surrender.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;British business must avoid hand-wringing and advocate in favour of settlement on the UK&amp;rsquo;s future status &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; quickly. As in today, as in right now. An “investment strike” is already underway. Deals are being abandoned, orders are being cancelled. Some of my former colleagues in the City have told me firsthand accounts of how their dealflow is drying up on account of #Brexit. Overcoming political paralysis to make a rapid decision in this direction will promote financial stability, inward investment, and London’s continued position as a financial services and innovation centre. Every day that there is delay will do further damage to this position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;This - investment strike - is what matters , not £ or FTSE.  Longer we faff around, worse it will be. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/EaPclJCp04&#34;&gt;https://t.co/EaPclJCp04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jonathan Portes (@jdportes) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jdportes/status/747146000385572864&#34;&gt;June 26, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are therefore getting behind the #EEAOption and encourage the rest of British industry - tech, banking or otherwise - to get behind it immediately, vocally, and forcefully. We also recommend supporting and engaging with the think-tank community and their advocacy work in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sincerely hope you will join us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eris Commercial Paper Bundles: Toolkit for Financial Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/31/commercial-paper-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/31/commercial-paper-intro/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;eris-commercial-paper-bundles-toolkit-for-financial-engineering&#34;&gt;Eris Commercial Paper Bundles: Toolkit for Financial Engineering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An introduction to smart contracts for the digital non-native.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hash&lt;/strong&gt;. Computers work because almost any kind of information can be transformed into a string of zeroes and ones called binary code. Once data has been reduced to binary code, computers can apply mathematical operations to it to produce reliable results. Cryptography involves passing the binary code of a piece of data through a series of arithmetic operations to produce a hash, an encoded string of letters and numbers that represents the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hashing is a one-way operation: while a certain data set will always produce the same unique identifier (the &lt;em&gt;hash&lt;/em&gt;), it is effectively impossible to do the math in reverse to decode the data from just the hash. One must have a key to access cryptographically stored information. Hashing and decentralized distributed data structures can be combined with business logic to make many kinds of applications, for example, value tokens. Value tokens, however, are just one way of using blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;. Smart contracts are cryptographically secure computational processes acting on cryptographically secure data in blockchain systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-s-the-big-deal&#34;&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s the big deal?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart contracts enable the technological evolution of existing legal concepts and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precedent&lt;/strong&gt;. Humans have long understood that history is our best guide, even when blazing new territory. Common law legal systems like the UK and US base their law, especially contract law, on &lt;em&gt;precedent&lt;/em&gt;, an earlier event that acts as a guide for subsequent similar circumstances. The collection, preservation and accessibility of legal precedent is a critical function of common law systems that will be enhanced by smart contracts that combine value creation, storage and transfer with logic and immutability of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authenticity, registries, sworn statements and real problems to solve&lt;/strong&gt;. Determining authenticity of data for the purposes of making business and judicial decisions is another critical job of legal systems. To support this, governments often establish registries that give an “official” version of authenticity for property and relationships that are of public importance. This reliable version of important facts allows for predictability and growth in commercial relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For legal proceedings, choosing what data to consider authentic when making decisions is a critical question. Historically, common law courts have relied on sworn statements of humans to establish significant facts. Large-scale failures of the current authenticity protocol for financial documents can have disastrous effects. For example, the ability to hide bad loans and produce bogus affidavits were important elements in the financial crisis of 2008. Smart contracts can both verify information in certain transactions more reliably than humans and allow a window into commerce for businesspeople and regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the promises of smart contracts is to limit the role of the middleman in commerce, reducing pain points that slow the velocity of money and retard growth. For example, legal due diligence for a simple purchase of company assets can involve checklists of information more than thirty pages long. In a mature smart contract system, these due diligence and compliance tasks may be more effectively and cheaply handled by smart contracts with access to immutable data registries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those whose job is to increase the amount of money in the financial system by creating investments, smart contracts may provide solutions to liquidity problems by reinventing the processes of trading and settlement. Freed from many drains on resources, businesses will be able to concentrate on growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big prize&lt;/strong&gt;. Smart contracts may not deliver the financial utopia many imagine, but they will deliver critical tools: increased data certainty and reliability of business processes. Data certainty means agreement as to the veracity and authenticity of evidence. It has the potential to eliminate the need to reconcile massive data systems and associated cost and delay. A cohesive approach to building such a mammoth blockchain system will require large-scale coordination across myriad sectors but is necessary to avoid a disjointed, siloed result that loses the benefits of smart contract technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;commercial-paper&#34;&gt;Commercial Paper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for commerce to flow, fungibility of value items is critical, as is careful typing and classifying of rights, obligations and objects. For a value object to function as currency, it must flow through commerce with as few strings attached as possible. Lawyers, businesspeople and governments have grappled with this issue for centuries - and one such set of tools that has evolved is &lt;em&gt;commercial paper,&lt;/em&gt; a type of debt obligation that specifically mimics the fungibility of fiat money while giving protection against adverse property claims (analogous to a cryptocurrency double-spend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial paper value is based on a promise and obligation to pay money in the future. The basic unit of commercial paper, the promissory note, may be recombined in infinite ways. The flexibility and reliability of commercial paper systems allows businesses to use these tools for growth. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/announcements/2016/03/03/r3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eris debuted commercial paper prototypes with over 40 of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest banks last month.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eris&amp;rsquo;s inaugural smart contract product, &lt;strong&gt;Eris Industries’ Commercial Paper Software Bundles,&lt;/strong&gt; combines the obligation-based building blocks of commerce with smart contract potential. The ability to create promissory notes, issue shares and keep track of assets creates the toolkit for financial engineering: out of these simple structures flow complex uses like time notes, demand notes, order paper, bearer paper, corporate bonds, securities, stocks, dividends, debentures, certificates of deposit, drafts, loan originations, repurchase agreements, mutual funds, reinsurance and equity options, to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crafted to work in multiple blockchain environments, Eris Commercial Paper Bundles deliver tools to build a strong smart contract use case system. Eris’s Commercial Paper is engineered for multidimensional applications, incorporating the lessons of history and precedent as well as the promise of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; Smart Contract Libraries subscriptions, please write us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@erisindustries.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;contact@erisindustries.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eris teams up with Ledger for blockchain hardware security</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/18/ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/18/ledger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;m cognisant that self-praise is no recommendation, at Eris Industries, we&amp;rsquo;re fast becoming the leading platform provider for enterprise blockchain applications - as evidenced by our recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/01/28/pwc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;strategic partnership with PwC&lt;/a&gt; and successful delivery of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/01/28/pwc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;commercial paper prototype&lt;/a&gt; system for 40 of R3 CEV&amp;rsquo;s 43 member banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That market, by itself, is already too large for any single company to service. And that market will grow, not shrink, as the range of possible use-cases expands. However, rather than try to own 100% of the stack or 100% of every relationship, we at Eris Industries choose to collaborate with the best companies in the market. Yes, we could try to &amp;ldquo;do it all&amp;rdquo; and then bill a lot more. However, by teaming up, we ensure that we do the job right, the first time. And that&amp;rsquo;s the best way to turn a bank into a marmot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; properly involves rather a lot more work than forking Bitcoin and bolting a slick UI onto it. Applied cryptography is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://iang.org/papers/fc7.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dauntingly complex&lt;/a&gt; discipline; consulting, legal thinking, engineering, and integrations all need to be brought to bear on a problem at the same time if you&amp;rsquo;re going to get one of these systems really humming along. Only by picking the right friends will you be able to build the right solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One huge problem facing blockchains (and cryptosystems generally) that not many companies are grappling with well is key management and hardware security. One company, however, is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why today we&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce that we&amp;rsquo;ve selected &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ledger.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ledger&lt;/a&gt; as our hardware security partner to help protect our clients&amp;rsquo; blockchain-based infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ledger is a technological leader in the blockchain security industry and provides a wide range of trusted hardware solutions for both consumer and enterprise usage. The company put itself on the map in 2015 with its best-selling smart card-based hardware wallet, and has since extended this to the B2B market with its TEE (Trusted Execution Environment) and HSM (Hardware Security Module) solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey Kuhlman, our CEO, commented for a joint press release issued on behalf of both firms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ledger is at the forefront of providing tools to secure blockchains and manage private keys. Ledger&amp;rsquo;s BOLOS platform is a crucial security offering which fills a vital security gap in the blockchain ecosystem. We are therefore very pleased to be working with Ledger, and together we will provide our users with the most flexible, capable, and user-friendly application development tooling in the market today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Eric Larchevêque, Ledger&amp;rsquo;s CEO, has some good things to say about us too. Which is nice. He commented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Eris Industries is a fast growing blockchain infrastructure provider for Fortune 500 customers. We are looking forward to deploying our solutions to their infrastructure and bring a strong layer of security to the management of critical workflows and cryptographic primitives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, press releases are always full of partnering companies saying nice things about each other, but in this case we certainly mean every word of it. 2016 has already been full of exciting developments in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We very much look forward to working with Ledger as we see just how much more exciting it will become.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40 banks and R3 run Eris</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/03/r3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/03/r3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/Eris_FOSS_Logo.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are very pleased to count 40 of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest banks and &lt;a href=&#34;http://r3cev.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R3&lt;/a&gt; among our users following the successful conclusion of the most recent blockchain experiment of the R3 Global Collaborative Lab. Many of the participants were already users, but the marmots always welcome more users into our burrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The R3 consortium is composed of 42 of the largest, most systemically-important banks in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-experiment&#34;&gt;The Experiment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All code for the base platform which we tested in the experiment is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eris-ltd/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt; and completely free for anyone to use. No modifications to the base platform were necessary to support the relatively complex experiment which included running a suite of well tested smart contracts against multiple blockchains with different collaboration settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experiment, reported in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/reuters/2016/03/02/business/02reuters-banking-blockchain-bonds.html?partner=IFTTT&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.wsj.com/cio/2016/03/02/key-blockchain-vendors-cloud-providers-square-off-in-major-test/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;, saw Eris Industries deliver a smart contract suite which demonstrated the automation of the issuance, trading, and redemption of commercial paper on a blockchain. The demonstrator used for the experiment, which relied on Eris&amp;rsquo; upcoming Smart Contract Libraries product to ease our own delivery time, was run and operated collaboratively - and concurrently - by 40 of the consortium&amp;rsquo;s 42 member institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockchain-interoperability&#34;&gt;Blockchain interoperability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue that we, as a company, have tackled head-on from day one is the idea of interoperability between blockchains and other distributed protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of industry players propose to solve this problem by over-engineering a standard kernel or &amp;lsquo;master protocol&amp;rsquo; of some kind which the community is magically &amp;ldquo;going to adopt&amp;rdquo;. This approach is a &amp;ldquo;winner take all&amp;rdquo; proposition which involves, e.g., a lot of discussion about which consensus mechanism is best, whether UTXOs or account-based systems are the future, or how many &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_many_angels_can_dance_on_the_head_of_a_pin%3F&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;angels can dance on the head of a pin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are, of course, placing our own early bets with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/philosophy/2016/03/02/eris-and-tendermint/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;design decisions&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, we believe strongly that there will be a great plurality of chaintypes designed to address different needs. Due to this philosophical approach we view such discussions around consensus mechanisms important for when applications move into production but wasteful effort before moving into production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we solve the interoperability problem with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hooking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;API hooking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;In a nutshell: Eris (Epicenter Bitcoin interview – Jan 2016) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/jtwztAtHj7&#34;&gt;https://t.co/jtwztAtHj7&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/GnIGNqlCgg&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GnIGNqlCgg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Antony Lewis (@antony_btc) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antony_btc/status/700307599137177602&#34;&gt;February 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t0AKC3wZdw4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Simples!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach means that Eris users can select whatever protocol works best for a particular part of an application - meaning they can select eris:db or geth for the smart contracts, and BigchainDB or other coming backends for high-throughput settlement, for example - and get them to work in concert without a great deal of effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate this, the experiment saw our prototype run on three different blockchains using two different blockchain designs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://erisindustries.com/components/erisdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eris:db&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethereum/go-ethereum/wiki/geth&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;geth&lt;/a&gt;. For the sake of history and clarity, we did not run the full demonstrator suite against geth due to differences in the client libraries between geth and eris:db and the time allocated to deliver did not allow for such a delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants were also given the opportunity to utilize the peer-to-peer hypermedia protocol &lt;a href=&#34;https://ipfs.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; if they chose. In this way we showcased the Eris Platform&amp;rsquo;s ability to work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eris-ltd/eris-services&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;completely different blockchain and distributed systems&lt;/a&gt; at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eris_ltd&#34;&gt;@eris_ltd&lt;/a&gt; stack w/ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/docker&#34;&gt;@docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dockermachine&#34;&gt;@dockermachine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/IPFSbot&#34;&gt;@IPFSbot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ethereumproject&#34;&gt;@ethereumproject&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tendermint_team&#34;&gt;@tendermint_team&lt;/a&gt;. Now w/ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BigchainDB&#34;&gt;@BigchainDB&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/04ETo5nZTp&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/04ETo5nZTp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Zach Ramsay (@cerebralbosons) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cerebralbosons/status/704329255203663872&#34;&gt;February 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey Kuhlman, Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; CEO, said of the successful conclusion of the experiment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Eris platform is designed to make it fast and easy for developers to create applications using any blockchain or other distributed systems. In this experiment our open-source tools successfully deployed suites of smart contracts on both a fully-permissionable ErisDB blockchain and an instance of a Go-Ethereum private blockchain. It was a pleasure working with R3 and we look forward to further experimentation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To our knowledge, it is the most extensive test of its kind ever undertaken, with R3 saying that the experiment marks an&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;unprecedented scale of institutional collaboration between the financial and technology communities exploring how distributed ledgers can be applied to global financial markets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-background&#34;&gt;Further Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This news follows sixty days of meaningful commercial and technical validation of Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; approach to blockchain technology, and the software we build, by a range of financial, professional services, and technology firms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In December, Eris was announced as one of the first blockchain software platforms onboarded by Microsoft &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/01/29/azure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Azure&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; cloud marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eris was also the first, and remains the only, blockchain platform available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/02/16/aws/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, last month &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/01/28/pwc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PricewaterhouseCoopers announced that it selected us&lt;/a&gt; as one of only three firms, and the sole smart contract provider, in its blockchain solutions portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;More important than any press coverage or corporate thinking, though, is what developers think. Last week Softpedia gave Eris v0.11 a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.softpedia.com/get/Programming/Other-Programming-Files/Eris.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;five-star rating&lt;/a&gt;, an accolade we&amp;rsquo;re pretty sure no other blockchain software in the world has attained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers, if you want to get started rolling your own blockchains today, please feel free to head over to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eris-ltd/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;documentation pages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.erisindustries.com/support/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;support forum&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial or media queries should be directed to contact@erisindustries.com in the first instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-eris-industries&#34;&gt;About Eris Industries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eris is the free and open-source Universal Blockchain Platform built by Eris Industries. Eris allows anyone to build their own secure, low-cost, run-anywhere applications using blockchain and smart contract technology. Our mission is to empower developers from a range of organizations to automate their data driven relationships using a variety of distributed systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eris is capable of running any client for a public blockchain, and any client for a permissioned blockchain which is open sourced. In this way, the Eris platform greatly reduces the difficulty of creating complex blockchain-based systems. With Eris, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to integrate multiple blockchain, distributed file storage, and other distributed systems into a single cohesive application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter which blockchain technology organizations wish to build on, Eris makes it easy to get started and provides developers with a cohesive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our offices in London, New York, and Berlin, Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; multidisciplinary team of lawyers, scientists, economists and engineers combines our respective areas of expertise to consistently deliver useful and fit-for-purpose blockchain tooling to Tier 1 global banks and other firms of global stature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eris Industries was founded in June, 2014 in London by Casey Kuhlman, Tyler Jackson, and Preston Byrne.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>