<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiring on Monax Industries</title>
    <link>http://localhost/tags/hiring/</link>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost/tags/hiring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>David is (Officially) a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/06/06/david-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/06/06/david-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to announce that David Braun has joined Eris as a software engineer on our applications team. He will be working out of our New York office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave has actually been a marmot for quite a long little while now. Although only recently did he move into being a full-time employed marmot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were first getting setup, we needed some contractors to help us get started. To get access to high-quality, vetted contractors we utilized a company called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toptal.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TopTal&lt;/a&gt; which we have been very happy with. Dave was one of the folks tasked with assisting to vet javascript programmers before they became authorized contractors within the TopTal ecosystem. He had also spent a lot of time working from various South American localities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When our listing went live within the TopTal ecosystem, Dave responded within an hour or two I think. He was extraordinarily excited about the possibilities of our tech for solving a range of problems he had experienced and in his extensive travels. I&amp;rsquo;m 99.99% sure we were the first company in our space to list on TopTal, but the majority of contractors within the TopTal network had never heard of &amp;ldquo;blockchain technology&amp;rdquo;. To be clear, this was in early 2015 when most of earth hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard of blockchain technology. But Dave had, and he was excited about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, there was a challenge. When Dave started working as a contractor for us, our platform was an utter and complete mess. So he got to work infesting the marmots with his perspectives on test-driven development and in how proper software production actually works. He told me during the early days that if he could impart one &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; to us that it would be the hard won lessons he&amp;rsquo;s learned over decades of building software. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure he said that with a mindset that he may be around for a few months. Indeed, he stuck around for more than a few months!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, Dave has been essential in helping our entire team to develop strong testing mechanisms that ensure our code does what it needs to do. He has been (thankfully) relentless in his pursuit of excellent software throughout his career, and has brought a unique and necessary perspective to our team. His perspectives and drive have provided much of the basis for turning our (admittedly) hacky early attempts into what we can proudly claim as actual software that is currently solving real world problems for our users and customers. And for this I&amp;rsquo;m very, very thankful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave&amp;rsquo;s duties for us will not really change. He has already been the maintainer of our javascript client library for a while now, and will continue in that vein. Secondarily, he will be helping with our experimentation around next generation smart contracts runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Dave and you should too! If you&amp;rsquo;re in New York feel free to buy him a green tea and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/06/06/paul-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/06/06/paul-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to announce that Paul du Plessis has joined Eris as a senior product manager on our success team. He started two weeks ago and will be working out of our Berlin office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul will be helping us in two primary, and very related areas. His primary duty will be as senior product manager. In this capacity he will provide the interface between our Library team who is responsible for building the smart contract bundles which provides the basis of our revenue side on the one hand and the sales team who is responsible for selling these bundles into the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great product manager acts as the interface between technical folks and sales teams. The product manager is able to package the benefits of a given &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; that is for sale in a manner which helps the sales team show buyers what problems are solved by the &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; in a cohesive and concise manner. It is a crucial role for a company seeking to sell into an enterprise setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it also works the other way. Pulling what the technical folks build and packaging for a sales team is only half the job. The other half of the job is to help the technical folks (in our case on our Library team which is led by Jan) understand what customer&amp;rsquo;s concerns and priorities are so that roadmaps can be agreed, produced, and communicated appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, product managers are the key to the &amp;ldquo;Conjoined Triangles of Success&amp;rdquo; (a concept which will be familiar to those that watch &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hbo.com/silicon-valley&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/triangles_of_success.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jokes about satire TV shows aside, Paul is uniquely suited to help us here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first advertised for the position which we eventually hired Paul to fill, I joked with Brian that it was the &amp;ldquo;ideas human&amp;rdquo; position. I am fairly sure that we received more applications for this role than any other role we have ever advertised. As part of the process, we asked applicants to provide an overview of a smart contract application (or, &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.erisindustries.com/eris/2016/06/05/ecosystem-applications/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ecosystem application&lt;/a&gt;) they would like to see built. There was a wide variety of answers, however Paul&amp;rsquo;s was one of the only applications which focused not on tokenizing and trading assets (where the &amp;ldquo;blockchain zeitgeist&amp;rdquo; has been for far too long). Rather, Paul&amp;rsquo;s response focused on the relational processes between ecosystem participants. An incredibly marmot-y answer indeed. It was a great start because we were really filtering for a grounded perspective as to logical entry points for our tech along with a clear storyline. And Paul delivered in droves from his first submission and through the entirety of the hiring process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working in insurance in South Africa where he hails from, Paul has recently completed his MBA and has been long interested in how blockchain and smart contracts technology can be used to improve processes which cut across participants in an ecosystem. This combination, of a strong business acumen along with an deep understanding of the technical capacity and limits of the technology we build, is exactly what we were looking for in a product manager. His experience in insurance will be vital as that vertical continues to learn about ecosystem applications and how this paradigm of building software can assist real pain points. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited to have someone with Paul&amp;rsquo;s experience and abilities on our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His secondary duty is to assist with project management on the one build-out we will be doing this year. This is very related to his product manager duties; although it is distinct from those. In the build-out which we are working on, we are working both with the client enterprise as well as one of their systems integrators. This paradigm, with our company providing our FOSS base platform and smart contracts, a systems integrator providing the middleware and front end, delivering to a subscribing enterprise client is one that we think is largely scalable. This project gives Paul a &amp;ldquo;coal faced&amp;rdquo; perspective on the pain points builders are currently faced that will be essential for his (and, of course, our) success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet as a company that is relentlessly focused on building and taking to market scalable products, the project management responsibilities Paul is currently embarking on are secondary in nature to his ultimate focus which will be in helping to refine, package, and roadmap our complex smart contract systems. Paul has a strong and clear focus, as do most of the marmots, on building actual products. This mindset is essential to our success in the market, and I for one am incredibly pleased that Paul has joined us to help extend our efforts and expand our capacity to deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Paul and you should too! If you&amp;rsquo;re in Berlin or London feel free to buy him a beer and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Interns Grow the Burrow</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/05/25/summer-marmots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/05/25/summer-marmots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce two summer interns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/samirpatellaw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Samir Patel&lt;/a&gt; joins us as a law student from MSU Law and will be helping out the libraries team with, among other things, the legal accuracy of our smart contracts bundles. My first introduction to Samir was a DM on Slack a few months back, asking for help setting up eris on his computer. After a little hand holding, Samir got things going and was (mostly) off to the races. #lawyerswhocode-eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other things, learning to program has this quirk of requiring one to learn a plethora of tools. One such tool, git, for version control, is essential and really ought to be a required class in high school (but I digress). So while passing through the region, I met up with Samir last month for a weekend of coding and &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.erisindustries.com/distributed%20business/2016/04/02/moving-the-chains/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Moving the (Football) Chains to the Blockchain&lt;/a&gt;. Yet another use case, though this one is particularly intriguing given the involvement of public funds in sport (stadiums). Hopefully he still remembers all those git commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Samir and if you&amp;rsquo;re in East Lansing or Toronto (yay, another Canadian eh), don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to buy him a beer and find out how to bring blockchains to sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://astro.temple.edu/~tue68607/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shuang Liang&lt;/a&gt; (Lexon) joins us as a PhD student in Android security from Temple University and will be helping out the platform team with setting up a viable IoT/ARM pipeline. Our first encounter with Lexon was through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.erisindustries.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Support portal&lt;/a&gt; where he was asking for assistance with building the docker images for ARM platforms, to get eris running on a RaspberryPi. A few pointers from Casey later and Lexon was deploying contracts to a multi-validator chain on a cluster of Pis. Impressed the marmots were with his substantial proof-of-work and intern Lexon became.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are very excited to have Lexon on board and the timing couldn&amp;rsquo;t be better as the supply-chain-on-a-blockchain (via IoT) space heats up. I was especially excited when we teamed up with EthEmbedded for day to get a feel for eris on the RaspberryPis first-hand. Save for a few to-be-expected work arounds, things when quite smoothly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/marmot?src=hash&#34;&gt;#marmot&lt;/a&gt; hack day in &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Guelph?src=hash&#34;&gt;#Guelph&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EthEmbedded&#34;&gt;@EthEmbedded&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phonikg&#34;&gt;@phonikg&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eris_ltd&#34;&gt;@eris_ltd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/blockchain?src=hash&#34;&gt;#blockchain&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ARMEmbedded&#34;&gt;@ARMEmbedded&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Raspberry_Pi&#34;&gt;@Raspberry_Pi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/j6d9LCs8cX&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/j6d9LCs8cX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Zach Ramsay (@cerebralbosons) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cerebralbosons/status/731999423346003968&#34;&gt;May 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since everybody loves demos and the IoT/blockchain space is hot right now, Lexon will be here in our Guelph satellite office next month to prototype an egg-delivery-by-drone blockchain application. The idea is simple: we have chickens and need to sell their eggs. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be fantastic if our customers could request delivery by sending a transaction to what we are affectionately calling: &lt;code&gt;eggChain&lt;/code&gt;, thereby alerting us to load the drone with a dozen eggs (and off it goes!)? Payment received, eggs delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s kinda cool, though what&amp;rsquo;s perhaps even more exciting is having IPFS running on a RaspberryPi, on a solar powered drone. Only then will files really be &lt;code&gt;in the cloud&lt;/code&gt;, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to equally great things from Lexon who&amp;rsquo;ll be working out of a top-secret lab in New Jersey this summer. Stay tuned for more details!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jason is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/05/12/jason-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/05/12/jason-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to announce that Jason Banks has joined Eris as a legal engineer on our library team. He started on Monday and will be working out of our Berlin office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first started Eris, I had a long conversation with our seed stage funders about who our target employees would be in the first few stages of our growth. One of the profiles we needed, which seemed insane in late 2014, was lawyer-coders. Those who sit at the intersection of law and code were rare in late 2014, and the market is not exactly saturated with these folks now. However, the market is also not absent such folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This human capital need was based upon our revenue model, which even at that time was the same as it is now: selling bundles of enterprise grade smart contracts to large enterprises (and, soon, startups as well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These smart contracts are bundles of business logic which sit on top of various blockchain clients operating various blockchain networks (thus, why Eris is &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/2016/04/03/wtf-is-eris/&#34;&gt;blockchain agnostic&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is all well and good in the abstract one may say, but how does one &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do that? &lt;strong&gt;Very carefully&lt;/strong&gt; is my usual answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often say that despite getting lumped into finTech as a &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; company, we are really a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/2015/09/15/smart-contracts-intro/&#34;&gt;legal tech company&lt;/a&gt;. Functionally, smart contracts populate the business logic layer for &amp;ldquo;ecosystem applications.&amp;rdquo; In other words, they&amp;rsquo;re about providing a system wherein the relationships amongst the actors involved in the ecosystem&amp;rsquo;s application are regulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this, whether we like them or not, is what lawyers do IRL. Lawyering is often a matter of &amp;ldquo;engineering&amp;rdquo; the fundamentals of a given relationship. Whether that relationship is a deal between two companies as evidenced by their contract, or the relationship is between an individual and a goverment as evidenced by legislation, lawyers are the professional group most involved in building the &amp;ldquo;terms and conditions&amp;rdquo; of relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To build legally compliant ecosystem applications we always analyze and understand how a system currently works as a first step. And to understand how complex relational systems actually work, one typically needs a legal background to be able to understand what the first principles are that drive the relationship. Then we have to distill those existing relational documents into code. But not just any code, most code monkeys could do that, but code that is modular, extensible, and scalable. And this is where having lawyer-coders starts to make sense. Because someone who understands (a) how current systems work, and (b) can distill those into modular code, that&amp;rsquo;s the person who can help craft a new style of building applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason has one of the most marmot-y profiles one could imagine. He started his professional career as a lawyer, first in New York and quickly thereafter in London. He worked in one of the stereotypical &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifeinbiglaw.tumblr.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;big law firms&lt;/a&gt;. Wingtips and all. Then he gave all his suits away and moved to Berlin to be a programmer. In Berlin, Jason worked as a javascript programmer, working to build usable web applications for other companies. He learned about modularity, do not repeat yourself (DRY in coder lingo), and extensibility from a developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective. Life was seemingly good. But then Ben moved across the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we hired Ben he said he would be willing to move to Berlin where we are focusing most of our engineering side hires in Europe. That was great for us as we had been planning to build out our team in Berlin anyway. So Ben moved to Berlin, and lucky for us got an apartment across the street from Jason. As one does with new neighbors they ended up chatting. Ben found out that Jason was a coder who used to be a lawyer and so began the recruitment insurgency campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ben told Jason more about what we do at Eris, how we approach the technology, and where we are going, Jason (luckily for us) saw the harmony between the two professional tracks he&amp;rsquo;d been on. Being able to build legally compliant systems not in word documents, but in a text editor using code is something that many, many lawyers have dreamnt about. Some consider such dreams nightmares, others consider them pleasant. But pretty much everyone that has done document assembly for numerous deals, particularly in finance, has seen how methodical it can be and has wished there were machines around to take out the drudgery of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason has been hired as our second legal engineer. He will be pulling from both streams of his background to help us build compliant, scalable, modular, extensible frameworks for complex financial instruments, workflows, and decision mechanics. All using smart contract technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason has built hundreds of finanical relationships during his time as a lawyer, from the simple to the most complex debt instruments available to very large companies. He has a keen understanding of how such systems work and will be using that knowledge base to help us, slowly but surely, build from the ground up modular frameworks for financial instruments that will allow our smart contracts to be used across a range of asset classes by a range of actors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonderful, exciting days are ahead of us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Jason and you should too! If you&amp;rsquo;re in Berlin feel free to buy him a coffee and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RJ is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/24/rj-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/24/rj-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to announce that RJ Catalano has joined Eris as a developer on our platform team. He started last week and will be notionally working out of our New York office, but remote from Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Eris, we have long been users of the Solidity programming language, however we have not been contributors to the language itself. This has always vexed us because we wanted to play a positive role in helping the language mature, where we were able.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Brian had a conversation with Christian, the maintainer of Solidity, about how we could contribute. Christian recommended that we get in touch with RJ. And so I did. Luckily for us, RJ was interested in chatting. After he successfully finished our not entirely fast hiring process and finished up his commitments to his previous employer he started this week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RJ is the final hire for the platform team in this round of hires. Once he and the rest of the new marmots get settled in, our platform team will be firing on many very interesting cylinders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RJ will be working with the tooling portion of the platform team. In particular, he will be taking over from me as the primary point person on our smart contract tooling. RJ is well versed in the mechanisms for how to work with suites of smart contracts from his time working on the Solidity compiler and other personal projects. These he did in his personal time, but now he will be doing in his work time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time I will be transfering maintainership of &lt;code&gt;eris:package_manager&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;eris:compilers&lt;/code&gt; over to RJ and he will be leading our efforts to smooth out the friction points for industrial applications of smart contract technology, at least with respect to the actual smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we move into exploring more deeply smart contract machines which are not Ethereum Virtual Machine based (which is on our workplan), he will be deeply involved in how the tooling operates in that new and largely undefined space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last major area that RJ will be assisting with is addressing needs which eris users have with respect to the Solidity language itself. RJ has already made significant contributions to the Solidity language, and we have long wanted to be &amp;ldquo;productive&amp;rdquo; users of that language by contributing where we can. We now have a marmot with the skills and ability to positively contribute rather than simply be &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.erisindustries.com/distributed%20systems%20for%20business/2016/02/03/on-open-source-banks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;only users&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, RJ is our most cryptocurrency friendly marmot, so he will likely be working on marmot-y outreach into that community where we feel we can add value to existing tooling and products in that space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from RJ and you should too! If you&amp;rsquo;re in Chicago feel free to buy him a coffee and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silas is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/23/silas-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/23/silas-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to announce that Silas Davis has joined Eris as a developer on our platform team. He started this week and will be working out of our London office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silas got in touch with us after Preston first started the Company&amp;rsquo;s public advocacy campaign against the #IPBill &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/2015/05/29/ei-comms-data-bill/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in the middle of 2015&lt;/a&gt;. As a privacy advocate he was impressed that a little start up out of nowhere was going on national radio (which, oddly, is still a thing) and strongly advocating against what the government said it was planning to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his first marmot-y move he sent me an email (at that time the contact@&amp;hellip; still came to my inbox) and said he wanted to chat. So we went out for a beer and talked for a bit. Alas, he was gainfully employed at the time with a quite hot startup so we&amp;rsquo;d have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, Silas got to know the marmots, and we got to know him. Although he was still working full time with his previous employer we went out for drinks now and again. After his startup &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networkworld.com/article/3031011/smartphones/why-did-microsoft-buy-swiftkey-hint-its-not-about-keyboards.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;exited&lt;/a&gt; he was ready for a new challenge. And so, this week, with great pleasure and a little fanfare he joins the marmots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silas will be working with the &lt;code&gt;eris chains&lt;/code&gt; team. His background in theoretical mathematics and machine learning (which is mostly what he was working on at SwiftKey) fills a gap in our current chains team. As chains grow in size and import, our ability to smoothly facilitate machine learning algorithms to be ran against the data held in blockchains increases in importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tons of points of interactivity between the space that blockchains occupy (namely, facilitating business process automation at a network level rather than individual enterprise level) and the space that machine learning occupies (namely, gleaning insights from large data lakes). Silas will be our lead in making sure that there is a smooth flow between these two paradigms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silas and Ben will be our primary point folks for the &lt;code&gt;eris chains&lt;/code&gt; product moving forward. There is a bucketload of work which is needed on eris chains as we continue to address the big current challenges in blockchains in our own marmoty way and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more pleased to have Silas on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silas will also be working with Rick on the ops side where needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Silas and you should too! Give him a shout &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/silas_davis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and if you&amp;rsquo;re in London feel free to buy him a coffee and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/17/david-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/17/david-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to announce that David Gardner has joined Eris as our Head of Partnerships on our success team. He started on Wednesday this week and will be working out of our London office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David is coming to us after a break in his &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; career (which he spent building a music studio!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After meeting with him for the first time and reading the &amp;ldquo;proof of work&amp;rdquo; he had submitted (we screen applicants by asking them to write a little bit before progressing to interview), I was sold that he was a marmot. I ended my notes with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final point: at one stage of the interview I asked&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: Theoretically when could you start should an offer be made?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Well, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing the job part time now for a little while already, so&amp;hellip; immediately&amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the kind of tenacity you want to see out of your business side team who will be responsible for laying the foundations of a sustainable, growth pattern for the marmot-y partners network we want to continue to build. Not only tenacity, but the resonance of what David prepared showed that for a non technical purpose he had a very keen understanding of the value which eris is providing into the market. And when you&amp;rsquo;re building a company focused on bringing value to developers, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t so cleanly translate to the non-technical folks. We know that since David &amp;ldquo;got eris&amp;rdquo;, that he would be vital to our efforts to &amp;ldquo;explain eris&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David will be helping us in two primary areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, and perhaps most obviously, given his title, he will be taking over as our point person for all partnership relationships. Given where eris sits in the stack, as the thing that folks build their blockchain applications on, it is incredibly important for Eris to have solid delivery and educational partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, for eris to succeed we have to be embedded in a healthy, flourishing ecosystem of different actors. These partnerships vary and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technical relationships around interoperability of components within the platform;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delivery partners looking to bring solutions to their clients and customers; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;educational and research groups looking to have reliable technology provider who has been at the forefront of the industrial applications of the techonology for a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a diverse group of folks. Each of which will have a different set of expectations they will be looking for out of their relationship with eris. David is just the human to manage all this complexity as he has a significant amount of experience working with companies both large and small all around the world. He has worked with technical and developer focused products all the way to consumer focused products and has consistently shown himself creative at bringing value into relationships. This makes him, we think, a natural fit for our Head of Partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, David will be helping out with a range of existing problem sets which the Success Team is facing right now. Watching steady growth in our Users is great for me as CEO and Head of the Platform team, but Brian&amp;rsquo;s Success Team as been, well, Brian. As the first full member of our success team besides Brian, there are a number of things which need tending to. David has not only helped big companies grow but has helped many small companies grow their demand side. Starting in the days when he helped a hard drive startup (which was really selling cinder block sized contraptions) move product. This makes him ideally suited to join our team just now because he can work &amp;ldquo;all over the stack&amp;rdquo;, except on the business side of &amp;ldquo;the stack&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from David and you should too! Give him a shout &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Philanosa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and if you&amp;rsquo;re in London feel free to buy him a coffee and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rick is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/02/29/rick-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/02/29/rick-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is my great pleasure to announce that Rick Dudley has joined Eris as a developer on our platform team. He started on Thursday last week (and he came not a moment too soon) and will be working out of our New York office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met Rick during a (now) humorous turn of events. I cannot remember exactly if it was the first or the second time we were on /r/bitcoin. But I do know it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/erisindustries/comments/304j9t/dear_rbitcoin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a &amp;ldquo;bloody&amp;rdquo; time&lt;/a&gt; in the history of the fuzzy little ground squirrels. Either way, at some point I saw &lt;code&gt;afdudley&lt;/code&gt; saying sane things about us. He didn&amp;rsquo;t totally get what the marmots were up to at that time but at least our vision was somewhat comprehensible to him. He also didn&amp;rsquo;t mind sparring a little bit, which made me smile. After that we chatted for a bit on IRC and generally saw each other around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night I met Jan actually was also the first night I met Rick in person. Over the months we&amp;rsquo;ve had a decent amount of chat and during the course of those interactions I have grown to respect Rick&amp;rsquo;s opinions on a good many things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was delighted the moment we received his application for Cloud Operations Engineer on the Platform Team. Although we have a multi-faceted, not entirely quick, hiring process, Rick sailed through and achieved consensus within our team in record time. We already knew he was a marmot. Indeed, we knew &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/3001ia/psa_if_you_as_hard_questions_or_criticize_eris/cpp1j2a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;he had been a marmot for a little while&lt;/a&gt;. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although he has done much thinking about consensus mechanisms and distributed computing applications, Rick&amp;rsquo;s self-confessed bread and butter is sysAdmin. Together this makes him a natural fit to work on improving our systems which have most of those characteristics that he enjoys pondering alongside the real world challenges of his &amp;ldquo;professional&amp;rdquo; life. This harmony we hope will lead to some amazing results as Rick gets settled in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rick will be helping us in two primary areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Rick will be taking over as our Operations Lead. In this capacity he will be assisting with the complex environments which our clients demand for their applications to be run. We have a wide range of clients, many who have quite strict security requirements extending both to on premise and cloud based environments. In this capacity Rick will have a range of devOps and sysAdmin responsibilities helping us properly integrate with (and troubleshoot where necessary) environments not administered by ourselves. He&amp;rsquo;ll also maintain ops responsibilities over our hosted services (mainly our compilers and ipfs gateways).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Rick will be working as product lead on our &lt;code&gt;Managed Engines&lt;/code&gt; product (which is what we used to call &lt;code&gt;Hosted Chains&lt;/code&gt;). We have a lot of ideas for how to improve a &amp;ldquo;managed eris&amp;rdquo; experience for our clients. We will be working on a product offering which will not only be true to our roots (hint, there will be smart contracts involved) but also actually addresses real world pain points that our users are about to face and will likely face in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect that he will also be working to craft tooling and identify pain points which arise when running complex environments and larger applications that embrace the eris philosophy of a &lt;code&gt;plurality of chains&lt;/code&gt;. And, as if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, he&amp;rsquo;ll probably (as my Scottish wife likes to say) &amp;ldquo;get his neb&amp;rdquo; into &lt;code&gt;eris chains&lt;/code&gt; a bit as we continue to refine and adapt that product offering to meet market demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Rick. Your ops team (and the rest of y&amp;rsquo;all&amp;rsquo;s team) should too! Give him a shout &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AFDudley0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and if you&amp;rsquo;re in new York feel free to buy him a coffee and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/02/08/nina-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/02/08/nina-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is my great pleasure to announce that Nina Kilbride has joined Eris as a developer on our libraries team. She will be working out of our New York office but will be working remote most of the time. I&amp;rsquo;m excited because today I get to move Nina from my super secret Twitter list I call &lt;code&gt;to hire...?&lt;/code&gt; to my less secret Twitter list &lt;code&gt;eris staff&lt;/code&gt; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many others in Eris I came to know Nina over the interwebs. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure this story begins on LinkedIn where Nina added me, and I am pretty sure I accepted and then forgot about it. Until a week or three later when I got one of those LinkedIn notifications that Nina had written a post. And it was about smart contracts. And it was delightful. And it was good. Wait a second, I thought, this is not just some bog lawyer. This lady sees some of the same things we&amp;rsquo;re seeing. That&amp;rsquo;s when she was added to the &lt;code&gt;to hire...?&lt;/code&gt; twitter list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do smart contracts well requires a venn diagram overlap of legal understanding and ability to code. This is not an overlap in which many folks are able to fall. But it is an area which, if we smart contract nerds are going to succeed, must be expanded. And Nina is just the person to help us start to expand that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nina will be helping us in two primary areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, even though she is a trained lawyer, you will note from the above she has been hired as a Developer. This is a big, courageous move and one which we hope will trailblaze the path for others to follow. Nina will not only be responsible for working with the subscribers to our libraries product to help them distill their legal obligations and business processes into specifications which we can code to and test for, she will &lt;em&gt;also have responsibilities to write&lt;/em&gt; (some of) &lt;em&gt;that code&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take note lawyers, code is coming for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nina, like the rest of our team at Eris, views smart contracts as a mechanism for enhancing our judicial systems, accountability mechanisms, as well as our business process assurance, and she brings a wealth of experience in real world legal problem solving (much of it at, as the coders say, the edge cases) which will be vital to our ability to assist our clients in their effort to take this technology to the next level. We all understand that it is one thing if the innovation team likes the idea, but if the system is going to be brought to production, risk, legal, and a whole range of other departments need to be on board. This is why it is important that our smart contracts team has a mix of real world legal problem solving as well ability to translate that into code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second area we are excited that Nina will be helping with is formalizing and systematizing our legal outreach efforts. This is going to be a big job, but if anybody has the knowledge, background, and communication abilities to pull it off, Nina just may be the human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Nina and you should too! Give her a shout &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NinaKilbride&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or on &lt;a href=&#34;http://cryptolawyer.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt; and if you&amp;rsquo;re in Raleigh feel free to buy her a coffee and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben is a Marmot</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/02/03/ben-is-a-marmot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/02/03/ben-is-a-marmot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is my great pleasure to announce that Ben Bollen has joined Eris as a developer on our platform team. Originally from Belguim, Ben will be working from our soon-to-be-opened office in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben is a physicist and developer by training with extensive experience working on distributed computing. Ben is coming to us most recently from Maidsafe where he helped to refactor the code base into its release-able RUST base code base. In his capacity as Developer for the platform team, Ben will be deeply involved in the building of a scalable, language agnostic, &lt;code&gt;eris chains&lt;/code&gt; smart contracts machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;rsquo;m excited about Ben&amp;rsquo;s ability to help us prove with certainty our ability to handle certain vexing problems we will face as we move to a much more modular, component driven chain design away from the monolithic designs that are currently available on the market. His approach to software building is a nice addition to our team, and his experience around privacy in distributed environments is a big win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben told me once that for him the &amp;ldquo;mission&amp;rdquo; that he was involved in was much more important than almost anything else in who he decided to reach out to regarding work. That means, ultimately, that he is a marmot at heart. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to great things from Ben and you should too! Give him a shout &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/benjaminbollen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and if you&amp;rsquo;re in Berlin feel free to buy him a beer and let us know how we can best help your organization get up to speed with the next generation of data and process management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>