<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eris on Monax Industries</title>
    <link>http://localhost/tags/eris/</link>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost/tags/eris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcing Legal Smart Contracts</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/08/18/enforcing-legal-smart-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/08/18/enforcing-legal-smart-contracts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;enforcing-legal-smart-contracts&#34;&gt;Enforcing Legal Smart Contracts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain smart contracts are a breakthrough development in the quest for a secure, interoperable technology to create data-driven solutions and conduct global commerce. This article outlines a beginning, multi-step framework for smart contract enforceability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockchains-for-legally-significant-relationships&#34;&gt;Blockchains for legally significant relationships.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain software architecture combines the security of cryptography with the resilience of distributed networks to create chain of authentic, reliable information about data-driven relationships. This process creates a permanent ledger of transactions that may be viewed by all participants in that particular blockchain system. Blockchains may be configured to suit multiple purposes across multiple verticals, enabling collaborative data solutions. The digital future includes a multitude of blockchain solutions with interoperable smart contracts providing the rules by which data-driven relationships operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains deliver proof of who did what when, what lawyers call evidence. They add to the legal engineer’s toolbox the groundbreaking element of data certainty, the ability to rely upon the authenticity and chain of title of a document stored in decentralized, cryptographic architecture. This seemingly small feat, proving documentary conditions, consumes a large amount of lawyer time in the form of authentication of records, establishing findings of fact[1] and auditing past events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart contracts are automated, logical, cryptographically secure processes acting on blockchain data. By combining certain evidence and rock-solid audit trail, smart contracts can automate legally significant actions based on if-then/if-else logic, saving significant time and money. They will enable automation of many everyday, business-as-usual commercial processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite enormous potential benefits, stakeholders are unlikely to transfer their valuable business from legacy infrastructure to blockchain systems without firm assurance they are not sacrificing any hard-won existing legal rights in exchange for smart contract efficiency. Legal engineers building blockchain systems must carefully consider the pre-existing judicial precedent and regulatory structures that govern potential use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;judicial-enforcement-of-electronic-contracts&#34;&gt;Judicial enforcement of electronic contracts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common refrain in blockchain industry reporting is a lack of legal standards providing guidance for those who want to deploy a smart contract-based system. From a former law practitioner’s perspective, this perception is generally incorrect. For many use cases, ample authority exists to conceive and build smart contracts within existing legal principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For smart contracts, the existing body of electronic signature and records law provides both enabling and regulatory frameworks that give legal engineers a baseline starting point. Legally significant smart contracts must meet or exceed existing standards for electronic contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic contracts have been vital parts of international commerce and finance since the end of the twentieth century, when many governments enabled electronic contracting through the authorization of electronic signatures.[2]  The e-signature language of the  United States’ Electronic Signatures In Global and National Commerce Act (“E-SIGN”)  contains typical language:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) a signature, contract, or other record relating to such transaction may not be denied legal effect, validity, or enforceability solely because it is in electronic form; and (2) a contract relating to such transaction may not be denied legal effect, validity, or enforceability solely because an electronic signature or electronic record was used in its formation.[3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, if the terms of an electronic contract are otherwise binding, an electronically signed contract meets signature requirements, therefore legal obligations may exist in dematerialized, electronic form. Similar rules were adopted by forty-eight U.S. States as part of the model law Uniform Electronic Transactions Act (“UETA”).[4] Across the globe, jurisdictions wishing to participate in the potential of electronic commerce over the internet enacted laws authorizing e-signatures.[5]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A signature is often a requirement for enforcement of legal contracts, so recognition of e-signatures created the opportunity to transition many kinds of enforceable legal relationships to electronic format. Enforceable e-signatures enabled the creation of many kinds of electronic agreements and the ability to trade them worldwide, including consumer contracts, service agreements and financial instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While e-signature law is largely uniform,there remains a significant degree of variation at the local jurisdictional level as to what agreements still require a traditional, pen-and-paper signature. For example, wills are excluded from most e-signature statutes. Real property records often require signed paper. Local variations are significant but not insurmountable hurdles to automated electronic contracts, underscoring the need for careful examination of specific laws when developing smart contract systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic contracts are increasingly important elements in commerce today. Courts regularly enforce electronic agreements. Dematerialization and interoperability of contracts and instruments is encouraged and mandated by regulatory authorities. The e-signature laws of the turn of the century are updating with more sophisticated tools. The foundation for enforceable blockchain smart contracts is strong and well-placed, ready to support innovative legal models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockchain-smart-contracts-are-fit-for-purpose-as-transferable-records&#34;&gt;Blockchain smart contracts are fit for purpose as transferable records&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The legal engineering inquiry into smart contracts systems does not end at judicial enforceability. Smart contract applications must comply with existing requirements for analogous electronic documents. Specifications and standards for systems that maintain data-driven relationships are produced by multiple actors like governments, regulators and ratings agencies. Read together, they are the framework that allow the transformation of e-contractual obligations into electronic securities and derivatives.  Blockchain smart contract systems can be configured to meet and exceed existing requirements for encryption, data integrity, audit trail and security, trimming operational costs while enabling new revenue models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One foreseeable blockchain application is creation and management of enforceable smart contracts. Enforceable contracts become assets that may be securitized, i.e. treated as collateral, and/or traded.[6] This process is a core function of existing electronic contract systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the United States, E-SIGN and UETA provide similar standards for creation and storage of transferable electronic documents, while other regulations like the Uniform Commercial Code (“UCC”) and securities law provide further guidance for specific collateral types.[7] One initial issue is whether blockchains can meet these statutes’ general requirements that a “single, authoritative copy of the transferable record exists which is unique, identifiable … and authentic.”[8] While it may at first seem counter-intuitive that a system based on a database existing at multiple nodes on a network creates a “single, authoritative copy” of a legal record, blockchain technology both satisfies and exceeds existing standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain smart contracts meet this standard via cryptographically secure content-addressable storage. In a process called hashing, data is passed through complex equations to produce a unique identifier. The hashing process is one-way, meaning no two sets of data produce the same outcome, and it is infeasible to decipher the hash to reveal the contents without a key. The distributed ledger provides the requisite immutability and audit trail.This combination produces the unique record of provenance, authority and control required by existing law, exceeding the capabilities of prior technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain technology fills the express needs for better electronic contract solutions. Both E-SIGN and UETA  avoid making specific technological recommendations in order to encourage further innovation. UETA notes in comments to the 1999 model law that the statute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I]s designed to allow for the development of systems which will provide “control” as defined in Section 16. Such control is necessary as a substitute for the idea of possession which undergirds negotiable instrument law. The technology has yet to be developed which will allow for the possession of a unique electronic token embodying the rights associated with a negotiable promissory note. Section 16’s concept of control is intended as a substitute for possession.[9]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jurisdictions are encouraging the use of blockchain technology to meet commercial data needs. As of this writing, the Vermont house is considering a bill that, among other things, treats blockchain documents as self-authenticating.[10] Delaware has launched an initiative to use blockchains in many registry functions.[11] U.S. federal authorities are considering explicit enabling of blockchain through legislation.[12] Globally, this phenomenon is reflected in the many nations exploring blockchain solutions for government and commercial purpose. Blockchain smart contracts are are well-suited to bridge the gaps in worldwide data driven relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;integrating-blockchains-and-legal-smart-contracts-old-questions-new-tools&#34;&gt;Integrating blockchains and legal smart contracts &amp;ndash; old questions, new tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing body of electronic contracts law gives a firm foundation to the first step in creating automated legal contracts: dual integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal in drafting legal smart contracts is predictability of rules-based results that allow businesses to create reliable future plans and products.[13] Traditionally, contracts may be made in any medium, including oral agreement. Enforcing oral agreements requires testimony of humans, an expensive and unpredictable process. Written contracts eliminate much of the uncertainty about enforcing a contract, because the terms are created at the time the contract is signed, not recreated from witness memory. The higher degree of reliability of paper writing led lawyers to develop a way to ensure that a contract means what it says and that it will be enforced as written: the integrated agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An integrated written agreement embodies the entirety of the parties’ contract. If a contract is fully integrated, evidence that would contradict or vary the terms of the written document is inadmissible, and a court is limited to the contract document in determining the intent of the parties.[14]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drafted properly, fully-integrated contracts may be proved solely by documentary evidence &amp;ndash; no testimony of humans other than document authentication is required or allowed.[15] Well-drafted contracts contemplate potential disputes and provide evidence for managing those disputes as simply as possible. Cumulative lessons of potential outcomes become boilerplate, the fine print that addresses as many “what-ifs” as possible. A tightly-drafted, fully-integrated contract has no loopholes in its performance and prevents time and money wasted on enforcement. It has a high degree of predictability in its outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure enforceability of legal relationships made in in blockchain data relationships, the simplest first step is to combine an integrated, enforceable contract with smart contract functions via dual integration. Dual integration links smart contracts and full legal contracts by reference to the contract’s storage address on the blockchain. Incorporating documents and objects by reference in legal documents is a familiar process to lawyers and delivers baseline enforceability industrial applications will demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart contracts can deliver today the reliability of existing e-contract procedures. Meeting existing standards enables us to iterate more complex smart contracts over time, creating safer, transparent assets, creating efficiency and liberating dark data. While Eris Industries is building increasingly automated legal contracts, since the company’s inception we have recommended dual integration as a reliable, scalable way to build enforceable smart contracts.[16]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-enforcing-smart-contracts-the-future-of-legal-engineering&#34;&gt;Self-enforcing smart contracts: the future of legal engineering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due diligence of dual integration accomplished, legal engineers are free to explore the next frontier of smart contracts: self-enforcing contracts. Enforceability means the right to apply to an actor with authority over the contracting parties to force the breaching party to pay or act. One limitation of self-enforcing smart contracts is scope: smart contracts can only enforce agreements to the extent that assets are known and held within the blockchain system itself. Currently, a legal smart contract must be coupled with judicial legal enforceability in order to be useful. Absent legal enforceability, if a contracting party breaches an agreement, she may simply avoid liability by not placing value into the system against which a promise may be enforced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is foreseeable that there will be many situations where on-chain enforcement is a viable and desirable tool, for example, in cases where collateral is held in blockchain form, where disputes are primarily documentary, and for purposes of broader cross-collateralization.[17]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-enforcing smart contracts, because of the variability in contracting procedures at local levels, are not yet amenable to a one-size fits all framework. Lawyers have long deconstructed deals and severed them into multiple, modular documents based on function. In order to create self-enforcing contracts, it is necessary for law-trained minds to deconstruct legal systems, actors, identities, property, governments, money and relationships. After deconstruction, legal engineers examine points in legal processes that may be augmented and automated through the application of smart contracts. In a legal process this means looking for objects, functions and deterministic, if-then/if-else logic to identify processes that can benefit from cryptographic data certainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The size of the legal engineer’s undertaking is tremendous, but it is proportional to the commercial value of automated contract provisions, decisions, and actions. The ability to apply logical legal processes to evidence using smart contracts opens the door to more complex legal agreements limited only by ability to define fact patterns and affect assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;See, e.g.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/rules/frcp/rule_52&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fed. R. Civ. Proc. 52.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Corbin on Contracts Sec. 23A1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/15/chapter-96&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;E-SIGN, 15 U.S.C. 7001(a).&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uniformlaws.org/Act.aspx?title=Electronic%20Transactions%20Act&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UETA&lt;/a&gt;; 4 Corbin on Contracts Sec. 23A1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;See, e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uncitral.org/uncitral/en/uncitral_texts/electronic_commerce/2001Model_signatures.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UNCITRAL&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999L0093:en:HTML&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npc.gov.cn/englishnpc/Law/2007-12/05/content_1381960.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.legislation.gov.au/Details/F2014C00010&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;See, e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/ucc/9/9-102&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Electronic Chattel Paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;See&lt;/em&gt;, E-SIGN, &lt;em&gt;supra&lt;/em&gt; note 3; UETA, &lt;em&gt;supra&lt;/em&gt; note 4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Id.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UETA, &lt;em&gt;supra&lt;/em&gt; note 4, Sec. 3, Comment 6.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://legislature.vermont.gov/bill/status/2016/H.737&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://legislature.vermont.gov/bill/status/2016/H.737&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/governor-markell-launches-delaware-blockchain-initiative-300260672.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/governor-markell-launches-delaware-blockchain-initiative-300260672.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-resolution/835/text&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-resolution/835/text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;See generally&lt;/em&gt; Lorna E. Gillies, Electronic Commerce and International Private Law: A Study of Electronic Consumer Contracts, Ch.2, Ashgate Publishing, Ltd (2013, 2016).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;See, e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, [UCC] 2-202](&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/ucc/2/2-202&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.law.cornell.edu/ucc/2/2-202&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Id&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/rules/fre/rule_803&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;F.R.E. 803&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://erisindustries.com/components/erislegal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; Dual Integration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-collateralization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cross-Collateralization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not legal advice. If you need legal advice, consult an attorney in your jurisdiction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eris Industries supports the EEA Option</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/06/27/eea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/06/27/eea/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Being a lawyer-led company, Eris Industries has a bunch of legal knowledge in-house - more so than most software companies. As such, we&amp;rsquo;re quick to form opinions about policy matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/jan/13/david-cameron-encrypted-messaging-apps-ban&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;very early opposition&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/2015/11/02/IPBill/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#IPBill&lt;/a&gt; eighteen months ago to our pro-remain position on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/02/16/getin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#Brexit&lt;/a&gt;, we take public positions on policy matters early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally we have thoughts on the EU membership referendum which occurred last week. You may have noticed that the people of the United Kingdom voted &amp;ldquo;Leave.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-tremendous-disappointment-for-british-business&#34;&gt;A tremendous disappointment for British business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any way you look at the &amp;ldquo;Leave&amp;rdquo; vote, it is a huge disappointment for British business. Two years ago, Eris Industries had three employees who worked out of our homes. Today, we have 17, with our head office remaining for the moment in London, an office in Berlin, and a subsidiary operating from New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are Europeans. Our team is French, Italian, Belgian, German, Swiss, English and Scottish. (American, Canadian, and South African, too.) We simply could not have assembled this team, and grown as we have, without the UK being a member of the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect wailing and gnashing of teeth on this issue across London and the UK over the coming weeks and months. Because the British people chose this outcome, denial is not productive. Nor is it a choice. As democrats we must accept that we are dealing with an exit from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we can mitigate. British and global companies can, and should, start considering our options and work towards adopting a common position. In Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; view, far and away the best option on the table is what the Adam Smith Institute calls the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamsmith.org/blog/time-for-the-eea-option&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EEA Option&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-we-support-the-eeaoption&#34;&gt;Why we support the #EEAOption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EEA option de-risks Brexit. It allows British business to thrive, and allows European and global business to deal with the whole of Europe - and the wider world - from their current bases in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are very sound business reasons to support this positon. As an information-age startup with a distributed workforce, when we started up in the UK, the UK&amp;rsquo;s membership of the single market made it easy for us to expand our operations on the continent with very little hassle. It&amp;rsquo;s always hard to find the right people. However, being able to hire in Germany, Belgium, and elsewhere meant we always managed to get our hands on the right candidates to help our business grow and expand into the world-leading blockchain technology provider we are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We and our employees benefit from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.polipedia.eu/tiki-index.php?page=Four+Freedoms+of+the+European+Union&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the four freedoms&lt;/a&gt;, especially those of free movement of labour and capital. If these freedoms are taken away, new, innovative businesses that follow in our footsteps will be hamstrung by stricter immigration restrictions, tax regulations, and compliance obligations, as well as reduced availability of investor funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom of movement is really the most critical piece. With it we can hire the best people Europe has to offer, and deploy them where we need them, when we need them, for as long as we need them to be there. Without it, our compliance costs would go up and we simply wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to get the right talent - because there simply isn&amp;rsquo;t enough of it concentrated in any one place in the European Economic Area. This includes London, which (as anyone in tech will tell you) is simply not the hub of global tech talent it fancies itself to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you see, Brexiteers, freedom of movement is not merely about holidays in the south of France or a shorter queue at the UK border. To be blunt, &lt;strong&gt;without freedom of movement in the EU/EEA, British firms cannot compete effectively in global markets.&lt;/strong&gt; The UK&amp;rsquo;s talent pool has proven far too small for our requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our conclusion is that the only compromise option that ticks the boxes in terms of business’ interests – from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;free movement of labour, to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the single passport for financial services, to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tariff-free trade with the EU,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which is also palatable from the perspective of the Brexiters and the much-beloved Scots, is the EEA Option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-others-should-support-the-eea-option&#34;&gt;Why others should support the EEA Option&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We therefore support the EEA Option &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamsmith.org/evolution-not-revolution&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(full paper here)&lt;/a&gt;, emphatically. We would encourage others to do the same, for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boris Johnson, Daniel Hannan, and Douglas Carswell – all free marketeers, each of whom are likely to have some say in what the outcome of the Brexit discussions are – have all hinted (or, in Carswell and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/eu-referendum-tory-campaigner-admits-brexit-immigration-some-control-a7102626.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hannan’s case&lt;/a&gt;, expressly stated) that continued membership in the single market is desirable. This is an entirely sensible and prudent position to hold and is in the interests of British business. We should let them know we support this position, which will substantially mitigate the damage of Brexit to British business, as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 48-52 defeat is not a mandate to withdraw from all trade relations with the EU and “go it alone” – the so-called “WTO Option” – but rather it is only a mandate to leave the EU. We owe it to the majority to leave, but they owe it to the (very large) minority to concede some middle ground. Compromise is hard, but needed, considering &lt;strong&gt;any exit will operate to unilaterally strip 16 million (!) British citizens, and British businesses, of EU citizenship and the rights and freedoms we currently enjoy and do not wish to surrender.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;British business must avoid hand-wringing and advocate in favour of settlement on the UK&amp;rsquo;s future status &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; quickly. As in today, as in right now. An “investment strike” is already underway. Deals are being abandoned, orders are being cancelled. Some of my former colleagues in the City have told me firsthand accounts of how their dealflow is drying up on account of #Brexit. Overcoming political paralysis to make a rapid decision in this direction will promote financial stability, inward investment, and London’s continued position as a financial services and innovation centre. Every day that there is delay will do further damage to this position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;This - investment strike - is what matters , not £ or FTSE.  Longer we faff around, worse it will be. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/EaPclJCp04&#34;&gt;https://t.co/EaPclJCp04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jonathan Portes (@jdportes) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jdportes/status/747146000385572864&#34;&gt;June 26, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are therefore getting behind the #EEAOption and encourage the rest of British industry - tech, banking or otherwise - to get behind it immediately, vocally, and forcefully. We also recommend supporting and engaging with the think-tank community and their advocacy work in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sincerely hope you will join us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fact Patterns, Predictions and Building Decentralized Organizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/06/18/fact-patterns-dao-legal-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/06/18/fact-patterns-dao-legal-engineering/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/crystal-ball.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fact-patterns-predictions-and-building-decentralized-organizations&#34;&gt;Fact Patterns, Predictions and Building Decentralized Organizations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a noisy one in the smart contracts world. The ambitious early Ethereum project, The DAO, blew up overnight as token holders found their accounts drained by a hacker. The DAO was the first large, for profit, decentralized autonomous organization deployed on Ethereum’s public blockchain, attracting more than $150 million worth of ether investment in its crowdsale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The response of in the blockchain community has been a mixture of shock and “I told you so,” especially from lawyers. In smartcontractland, lawyers generally opined that The DAO iteration was too unstable for deployment and said so noisily in blogs and social media. The developers saw a bug, well in advance of release. The lawyers saw a different problem: the DAO loudly eschewed risk management because of the self-executing nature of smart contract code. Lawyers warned that risks for participants in the event of failure ranged from losing their investments to enormous civil liability and possibly jail. Undaunted, the DAO deployed anyway. Here be dragons indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawyers predicted the organization’s implosion based on their knowledge of &lt;em&gt;fact patterns&lt;/em&gt;, that is, the tendency of human relationships to repeat, in cause-and-effect succession, recorded over centuries by the legal system. Common law attorneys learn primarily by studying fact patterns of prior relationship failure to recognize recipes for disaster and avert course accordingly. Fact patterns allow lawyers to distance ourselves from the human stories that might otherewise cloud our analysis and judgment so we can make clearer decisions. In The DAO’s case, red flags were obvious: unlicensed actors in regulated space, refusal to plan for what might happen in the event of a failure and lack of testing. Lawyers also calmly accept that you just can’t convince some people, and the law will be there to both clean up the mess and tell us how to avoid the same problems in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it didn’t have to be this way, with a little attention to risk management and legal engineering. The same fact patterns that informed lawyers’ prediction of problems with The DAO give us models on which to build, to experiment, to push the limits of blockchain relationships. Risk management and legal engineering allow us to plan how we build according to the succession rules of “what might go wrong?” In legalese, it&amp;rsquo;s about &lt;em&gt;foreseeablility&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since inception, Eris has led the way on decentralized organization development. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the things that made me want to be a marmot, the company&amp;rsquo;s clear-eyed view on &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; do DAO and its vision of the huge potential of DAO done right. As &lt;a href=&#34;https://prestonbyrne.com/2016/05/17/thedao-dont-walk-away-restructure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Preston Byrne wrote recently&lt;/a&gt;, the blockchain decentralized organization model is worth fixing. Despite manifest risk, people around the globe poured money into The DAO project, demonstrating the traction of cryptographic code-based organizations bringing global actors together to achieve a purpose. The time for decentralized organizations is here. The DAO debacle is a testament to the crucial need to get corporate governance right and a test of the governance of Ethereum as a whole as it weighs its response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is not an “I told you so,” rather, it is an exploration of the value of the fact pattern in both making predictions and building stuff for human use. The DAO fact pattern reinforces these law school lessons: 1) blockchains, like all human undertakings, are not special snowflakes; and 2) the best way to change the law is to learn its rules and carefully direct their evolution, use case by use case. To build new models that humans use, we must study, and learn from, human fact patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain, Timestamps and the Art of Legal Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/06/15/blockchain-timestamp-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/06/15/blockchain-timestamp-engineering/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/Louisville_Kentucky_1861_cover+3c.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;blockchain-timestamps-and-the-art-of-legal-engineering&#34;&gt;Blockchain, Timestamps and the Art of Legal Engineering&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the core functions of blockchain technology is the ability to timestamp every transaction, that is, to determine “*who did what when?*” The importance of this underlying proposition for legal applications is fundamental. One of the jobs of a dispute resolution system is to determine who performed what act at what time when relationships break down. The outcome of a legal dispute often turns on such a determination. In the olden days, contracts were made in person and an offer became a contract when the acceptance was received by the offeror. This meant that in a dispute the effective timing of contract was a question of fact for a judge or jury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawyers and judges quickly determined that solving questions of &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;who did what when&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; via legal fact-finding (judges and juries) was inefficient and added no value to the system if the effective acts could be determined by reliable outside evidence. Additionally, a set of freely available rules based on this evidence would allow parties to predict the outcome of  a result and resolve their own disputes accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the &lt;em&gt;mailbox rule&lt;/em&gt;, altering traditional negotiation structure for contracting via post: an offer made by mail is not effective until received by the offeree; acceptance is effective as soon as it is placed in the mailbox by the offeree; for revocation to be effective, it must be received by the offerer before they post a letter of acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mailbox rule arose when contract negotiations were often conducted by mail and it was not necessarily possible to determine when the parties had reached mutual assent. Latency, that is, time the contract messages spent in transit, meant that parties might change their minds about critical terms before the elements of a contract were complete. The mailbox rule used the typical elements of postal timestamp, offer and acceptance to determine when a contract was effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mailbox rule, a deviation from existing contract rule, created predictability. Parties could look at the written evidence before them in terms of timestamps and content and determine when and if the elements for contract formation were present. Predictability obviated the need to bring a fact-finder into the process and saved litigation costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mailbox rule, far from being an anachronism of the postal age, scales to electronic commerce. I’ve both won and settled lawsuits involving electronic messages using mailbox rule case law. Blockchain timestamps and an immutable stream of data are more effective than postal stamps and human sworn statements to prove when a legally significant communication took place. Blockchains and smart contracts provide certain evidence of timing and authenticity. The mailbox rule will flex to guide blockchain commerce, even as the latency that necessitated it decreases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mailbox rule is a centuries-old example of legal engineering, that is, creation of new rules that build on existing models, evolving them to fit current tools and future relationships. While the need for lawyers to build engineered systems is particularly pressing as we change from one commercial medium to another, the concept of legal engineering is not new. Case law systems, modular statutory code, digest systems, commercial paper, uniform best practices standards and computerized legal research are just a few world-changing and prediction-enabling achievements of legal engineers over the years. Blockchain smart contracts bring new tools to the ancient art of legal engineering and new possibilities for fostering development of commercial and human potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are ecosystem applications?</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/06/05/ecosystem-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/06/05/ecosystem-applications/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/frenchy/4469177031/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/ecosystem_applications.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a long piece. Come back to it when you have some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to all those who helped shape and mold my thinking in this area. You (mostly) know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew Anthemis would be a wonderful fit for our company the moment that Sean Park, one of its Founders, started talking about ecosystems; which was, IIRC, the first day I met him. Sean is a believer in ecosystems and networks as a way to achieve scale in the information age where bigger &lt;code&gt;!=&lt;/code&gt; better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my part, I&amp;rsquo;ve also long been a believer that being able to understand how ecosystems operate, change, and evolve is the differentiating skillset necessary to achieve success within environments where levels of complexity are high. And information age economies have a &lt;code&gt;lot&lt;/code&gt; of complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-the-industrial-age-information-age-transformation&#34;&gt;Context: The Industrial Age =&amp;gt; Information Age Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continue the march from the industrial age to the information age a number of things are starting to matter less than they once did and a number of other things are starting to matter more than they did before. The tectonic plates of globally-focused businesses, digital nomads, and information abundance have combined to massively transform a range of industries already and are hardly finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes, which will take a generation or two to fully play out (much less to fully understand), originally powered the first generation of collective process management tooling which was focused on providing the base business process automation for a given &lt;strong&gt;enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;. This generation of tooling, led by companies like SAP, Oracle, and others, effectively leveraged economies of scale over data and data processing power which on-premise data centers could provide. This generation of software emphasized the enterprise as the center of the universe. Or, something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/Bartolomeu_Velho_1568.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These same changes later powered the second generation of collective process management tooling which is focused on extending the benefits of software defined process automation into &lt;strong&gt;smaller businesses&lt;/strong&gt;. This generation of tooling, led by companies like SalesForce, Xero, Github, and others, effectively leveraged economies of scale over data and data processing power which IaaS systems could provide (until they eventually needed their own data center). This generation of software emphasized the &amp;ldquo;App&amp;rdquo; (or, latterly, the &amp;ldquo;Platform&amp;rdquo;) as the center of part of the universe. Or, something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/dandeluca/2908872934/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/banksy_rat.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our view we are entering into the third generation of collective process management tooling which will focus on extending the benefits of software defined &lt;strong&gt;relationships&lt;/strong&gt; for businesses of many different sizes. This generation of tooling, which will be led by the companies we currently label &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;smart contract&amp;rdquo; companies, will leverage the economies of redundancy over data and data processing power which networks of peers can provide. This generation of software will emphasize the &amp;ldquo;Ecosystem&amp;rdquo; as the center of part of the universe. Or, something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/16210667@N02/11665732305/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/walking_on_trains.jpg&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;small-is-hot-big-is-not&#34;&gt;Small is Hot; Big is Not&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to move forward with the next generation of collective process management tooling, we need to understand what are the big challenges which businesses face. This requires there to be a marmot-y hypothesis around where business is going. The remainder of this section is my own thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest changes which has only just begun, is in the likely reduction in competitive economies of scale for large producers of goods. Increasing equalization of labor and resources costs in a truly globalized economy are very likely to create a context where one of the great cost differentiators for the production and distribution of physical products is transportation. This is, in turn, likely to require many supply chains to move toward smaller producers hooked into a range of distribution networks from local to global in scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As 3D printing, makers shops, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://continuations.com/post/145503327830/the-coming-paradigm-shift-in-manufacturing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;manufacturing automation&lt;/a&gt; continues to equalize the ability of smaller producers to &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.erisindustries.com/tutorials/2015/08/05/eris-services/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;competitively build&lt;/a&gt; physical products and as technology such as automated air and ground transportation along with increased &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kpler.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shipping efficiency&lt;/a&gt; continues to equalize the ability of smaller producers to &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/hiring/2016/05/25/summer-marmots/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;competitively distribute&lt;/a&gt; physical products, it is highly likely that smaller producers will gain in relative power to larger producers for many types of goods in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collectively the above two paragraphs coagulate into the idea that smaller producers will have advantages in the information age which they lacked in the latter industrial age due to their smaller scale. There will of course be exceptions to this, but mostly the above will be a techno-philia change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing tastes also play a role. For example, and I admit this is a subjective comment but still, most folks I know would prefer locally sourced &amp;ldquo;ingredients&amp;rdquo; when given a choice. It is becoming increasingly clear that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.authenticbrandindex.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;brand authenticity&lt;/a&gt; is one of the major differentiating factors when consumers are faced with a paradox of choice. In other words, a &lt;strong&gt;connection&lt;/strong&gt; to a given producer&amp;rsquo;s brand is increasingly important to consumers. One theory as to the driver of this change is that it is due to the fact that, at the end of the day, we are social creatures, and that we crave the human connections embedded in how we go about our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collectively the above paragraph coagulates into the idea that authentic producers will have advantages in the information age which they lacked in the latter industrial age. There will of course be exceptions to this, but mostly the above will be a techno-phobic change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These vectors align in the direction that small is &lt;em&gt;hot&lt;/em&gt; and big is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;. Big box stores are dying; malls and one-stop-shops are not far behind. Big law firms are losing lawyers to smaller, niche firms. Small agriculture is (again) a thing. And smaller app-based banks are beginning to eat away at large banks&amp;rsquo; customer bases. The &amp;ldquo;sharing economy&amp;rdquo; across the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while, from a philosophical perspective, I&amp;rsquo;m in alignment with small, local, and genuine, that simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By way of a simple example, a small business in some portion of the world can always list their products on the internet. By doing so they have an ability to find customers, prepare shippings, and deliver to a global customer base. This is elegant. Yet it is not totally realistic for the vast majority of small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus the theory behind EBay, Amazon, and Etsy&amp;rsquo;s successes &amp;ndash; they act as the front office of a global customer base and the small business just needs to act as the back office (and also make good products). But Amazon, et al., do more than act as the front office. They also run &amp;ldquo;the platform&amp;rdquo; on which these small businesses can sell their goods. These &amp;ldquo;platforms&amp;rdquo; will list products, process transactions, provide customer servicing add-ons, or whatever suits the business of &lt;em&gt;the platform&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, and I finally have come full circle to software, if we are truly in a globalized world where small and/or authentic matters more than big and/or bland, how do the small and authentic work together instead of &lt;em&gt;having&lt;/em&gt; to rely on &amp;ldquo;the platform&amp;rdquo;? What if they want to run &amp;ldquo;the platform&amp;rdquo; themselves by banding together? As an ecosystem. How can they build applications that run on an ecosystem level, or, as we call them &lt;code&gt;ecosystem applications&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of this post will look at that question in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blockchains-and-smart-contracts-two-toolkits-for-building-ecosystem-applications&#34;&gt;Blockchains and Smart Contracts: Two Toolkits for Building Ecosystem Applications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem that blockchain technology solves is not electronic P2P cash, nor is it settlement latency, it is the problem of &lt;code&gt;attribution and ordering of inbound events; at an ecosystem level&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I send someone a bitcoin, what am I &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m signing a message which says that &amp;ldquo;I, keyholder of key X, am transfering title over &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lsquo;object&amp;rsquo; (in the example&amp;rsquo;s case, a bitcoin) to the keyholder of key Y.&amp;rdquo; My signed message then is broadcst across the network. The network then analyzes this message to determine if the message has been properly signed and if it has, then the network transfers title over the &amp;ldquo;object&amp;rdquo; in question to the keyholder of key Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, in bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s case, there is a censorship-resistant, permissionless network behind all of it, but that is not the interesting bit in my view. To me, the interesting bit is that the network, without relying on passwords or logins, is able to effectively attribute actions. See passwords and logins cannot safely be &amp;ldquo;held&amp;rdquo; at a network level. In traditional software architecture, they can be safely &amp;ldquo;held&amp;rdquo; by an application that is designed to run under the control of a single entity. Yet, if we take away the assumption that there will be a single arbiter of the password then we need to utilize a different system for attribution. We also need to remove the assumption that our application can rely on IP Addresses. In traditional architecture, this provides a backup for determining attribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of keeping a single holder of our passwords or IP Addresses when we  build applications that operate on an ecosystem level we rely on digital signature algorithms and elliptical curve cryptography. This technology, in combination with the ordering and timestamping functionalities that validators (or, in POW chains, miners) provide, solves the first problem ecosystem applications have: &lt;strong&gt;the problem of who did what when&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When blockchains are analyzed under this paradigm, their &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byzantine_fault_tolerance&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BFT&lt;/a&gt; consensus algorithms (implemented in a variety of ways) and their &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_key_infrastructure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PKI&lt;/a&gt; provide a nice abstraction for application makers to begin building applications that run on an ecosystem level and need to know, well, &lt;code&gt;who did what when&lt;/code&gt; (without utilizing passwords or IP Addresses) in a reliable, resilient manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the key difference in how blockchains and more simple fault-tolerant databases (such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rethinkdb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rethink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/basho/riak&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;riak&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/coreos/etcd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;etcd&lt;/a&gt;) which are also able to solve the problem of &amp;ldquo;who did what when&amp;rdquo;? The difference is an assumption about the network configuration. These fault-tolerant database technologies assume that the network is controlled by a single entity. Raft, the consensus engine used by these databases, is what&amp;rsquo;s known as &lt;code&gt;fault tolerant&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; or &lt;code&gt;FT&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; rather than &lt;code&gt;byzantine fault tolerant&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; or &lt;code&gt;BFT&lt;/code&gt;. The difference between &lt;code&gt;FT&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;BFT&lt;/code&gt; is important. The primary difference is a diffusion of power over who is the final arbiter of &amp;ldquo;who did what when&amp;rdquo;. Makers of FT databases such as rethink, riak, and etcd have also been able to rely upon security assumptions about how their network and permission environment is configured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains, whether unpermissioned or permissioned, do not assume that there is a single entity controlling &amp;ldquo;what the data is&amp;rdquo; (or, alternatively phrased &amp;ldquo;who did what when&amp;rdquo;). And this is not a small difference in the design assumptions. While it is true that modern, fast, blockchain technology is &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt; closer to rethink, riak, or etcd in how they approach a number of underlying technical problems than they are to bitcoind, even the newer, faster chains do not relax the assumption that the data is going to be held &lt;strong&gt;across&lt;/strong&gt; entities rather than &lt;strong&gt;within&lt;/strong&gt; entities. This is exactly why they are being thought of as one important tool for opening up a range of new applications &amp;ndash; applications that run cohesively at an ecosystem level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;attribution&lt;/em&gt; problem that blockchains solve is insufficient, alone, to actually be able to build coherent applications that run on an ecosystem level beyond very simple applications; such as moving electronic cash from one person to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next problem that needs to be solved is &lt;strong&gt;deterministic computation&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the problem that the &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; the community currently calls &amp;ldquo;smart contracts&amp;rdquo; solves. At least according to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coindesk.com/making-sense-smart-contracts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the definition we adopt&lt;/a&gt;, the problem that smart contract technology solves is not escrowing funds, it is the problem of &lt;code&gt;is computation happening in an agreed manner&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by deterministic computation? I mean that all participants in the ecosystem need to be able to compute something and achieve the same result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds rather easy at first blush, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that what computers are supposed to do? It is indeed, for the most part, what computers do. However, computers are designed to perform computation, not deterministic computation. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the two major sources of non-determinism in an effort to understand why we need to control them in order to avail ourselves of a method to build ecosystem applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first major source of non-determinism is randomness. Every programming language I know of has a way to &amp;ldquo;make&amp;rdquo; a random number so that one can perform operations on it. Programmers use these random numbers to accomplish a variety of programming tasks. And yet, if one were to allow randomness within a strongly deterministic system of computation, all the members of the ecosystem who were running the application would &amp;ldquo;make&amp;rdquo; a different random number as the basis for the computation task. This means they would then have a different outcome for the entire computational sequence which depended on the random number. When one is trying to ensure that computation achieves exactly the same result across the ecosystem that is a bug, not a feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second major source of non-determinism is time. Every programming language also has a sense of time. This allows programmers to do stuff like get &lt;code&gt;timeNow()&lt;/code&gt; and add a few days to create a filter of upcoming events. This is all well and good, but it is unlikely that the members of the ecosystem will have their computer clocks so finely tuned that they are &lt;strong&gt;exactly&lt;/strong&gt; the same &amp;ndash; down to the millisecond. One of the features that we design for when thinking about ecosystem applications, is that they can and should be verifiable by later in time participants. For example, if the ecosystem is in a highly regulated industry, then auditors for the various participants in the ecosystem may need to perform an audit on the year&amp;rsquo;s activities. The &lt;code&gt;timeNow()&lt;/code&gt; at the end of the year will very much &lt;em&gt;not equal&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;code&gt;timeNow()&lt;/code&gt; when the computation was originally performed. This will result in auditors getting a different result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we can take these sources of non-determinism out of the computation layer, then we can build systems where multiple actors in an ecosystem can, in real time or later in time, verify and notarize that a computation has happened in an agreed manner. But in order to &amp;ldquo;verify and notarize&amp;rdquo; a computational sequence, we must have what I call &lt;em&gt;deterministic computation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other problem that smart contract technology solves, is a distribution problem. In order for ecosystem participants to perform the computation, they need to &lt;strong&gt;have&lt;/strong&gt; the computational sequence. In &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; computing we solve this by either: (a) installing applications on a given device; or (b) all connecting to the same cluster of devices where an application has been installed and is running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with ecosystem applications, we typically solve this in a different way. We often, but not always, put the application&amp;rsquo;s logic &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; the blockchain. We use the immutability characteristics of chain tech along with a smart contracts interpreter (often called, a VM (for virtual machine)) to not have to worry about downloading and installing these computational sequences. We simply connect in to the ecosystem&amp;rsquo;s network and go vroom!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-lakes-message-queues-and-pkis-three-more-toolkits-for-building-ecosystem-applications&#34;&gt;Data Lakes, Message Queues and PKIs: Three (more) Toolkits for Building Ecosystem Applications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While blockchains (providing us &lt;code&gt;who did what when&lt;/code&gt;) and smart contracts (providing us &lt;code&gt;deterministic computation&lt;/code&gt;) are two tools that give ecosystem application builders two main capabilities necessary for building ecosystem applications, we still have a few more base requirements to really enable this technology to flourish. Namely we need to solve &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;privacy&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In applications that are built on traditional architecture we can have content which resides on a single device or a cluster of devices that is under the control of a single entity. If that entity decides, for whatever reason, to stop servicing an application or stop serving particular content, it can so decide unilaterally. However, when we are building applications meant to exist outside the control of a single participant within the ecosystem, we cannot make such an assumption. This is where the IPFS project&amp;rsquo;s thoughts about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ipfs.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;permanent web&lt;/a&gt; are so crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How we will deliver and store content within our ecosystem application is only one portion of the content problem. The other is how we &amp;ldquo;relate&amp;rdquo; to it. In other words, how do we know that &amp;ldquo;this is &amp;lsquo;it&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; whatever &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rdquo; may be. In computational terms this is solved by &lt;strong&gt;content addressable storage&lt;/strong&gt; and it is the one of the key components for how to think about designing ecosystem applications. No matter how we deliver and store content, we need to be addressing the content with precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content addressable storage gives us, in general, assurances that &amp;ldquo;this is &amp;lsquo;it&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;. In traditional architecture when we are retrieving files from a remote server (to download an app, or to load a web page), there is always a risk that either the remote server was hacked in some way, or the file was &amp;ldquo;swapped&amp;rdquo; while it was on the wire between the remote server and your device. Depending on whether we trust the pipes (this is, for the record, part of what &lt;code&gt;SSL&lt;/code&gt; gives us) and/or whether we trust the remote servers&amp;rsquo; credentials (that it is, e.g., Apple, Inc. is the company behind apple.com, the other major part of what &lt;code&gt;SSL&lt;/code&gt; gives us) we may need to take further actions to ensure that what was downloaded is &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rdquo;. Although SSL is a well worn system, if we want to be very careful that &amp;ldquo;this is &amp;lsquo;it&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; what we do is after we download a file from the internet we take its hash (which can be thought of as the &amp;ldquo;fingerprint&amp;rdquo; of a file) and compare that hash to one that has been provided by the publisher. This allows us to (if we trust the publisher) ensure that what we downloaded is what the publisher produced. When dealing with content addressable storage, which is local to your device, you can have assurances that the file was not &amp;ldquo;swapped&amp;rdquo; and that the file is pointing at what the network would like one to point at, because in most content addressable systems we reference data by its hash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final, major, challenge is around privacy. There are two types of privacy which are necessary to examine. The first one is a &lt;code&gt;me only&lt;/code&gt; type of privacy. This means that there need to be things which are known only to me. We typically define these as secrets. Secrets are things like one&amp;rsquo;s private keys, or logins, or other information which should be available only to you. Those things are necessary for ecosystem applications. Within the Bitcoin world, wallet software provides a very valid &lt;code&gt;me only privacy&lt;/code&gt; function. There are a range of possible options for how to build generic ecosystem applications while also enabling &lt;code&gt;me only privacy&lt;/code&gt;. However, mostly ecosystem applications only need to &amp;ldquo;interface&amp;rdquo; with the generics so these will not be covered in great detail here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second type of privacy is a &lt;code&gt;come over here I want to tell you a secret&lt;/code&gt; type of privacy. Because within ecosystems, we don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily assume that all participants &lt;code&gt;need/want/have_a_right&lt;/code&gt; to have all the information about all the things. This is where private message queues (or, as some may call it p2p messaging) and an authenticated public key infrastructure (a PKI) with a given identity mechanism comes into play. Private message queues give us the &lt;code&gt;come over here ... a secret&lt;/code&gt; part of the whole problem. An authenticated PKI solves the &lt;code&gt;**I** want to tell **you**&lt;/code&gt; part of the whole problem. These two toolkits, message queues and a PKI give us the final piece of what, at least theoretically, is a complete look at the components necessary to build most ecosystem applications. (For the record, if I was sitting in SWIFT&amp;rsquo;s position I&amp;rsquo;d be focusing resources on these tools rather than blockchains.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A summary table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nerdy term&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;blockchains&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;who did what when&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;attributable data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;smart contracts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;computation that happens in an agreed manner&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;deterministic computation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;data lakes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;what content are we talking about&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;content addressable storage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;message queues &amp;amp; PKIs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;come over here I want to tell you a secret&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;shared secrets&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-ecosystem-applications-run-on&#34;&gt;What Do Ecosystem Applications Run On?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short answer is that nobody really knows. There are two competing ideas within the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea one is that a &lt;em&gt;single binary&lt;/em&gt; so beautiful enough and wonderful enough connecting into the &lt;em&gt;one network&lt;/em&gt; that is so perfect and fitting for all needs that everything will just run it, and then all participants from all ecosystems seeking to build ecosystem applications will simply turn on that binary, and do whatever they need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, for lack of a better metaphor, the OSX style of ecosystem applications. In the OSX style, the magic binary of wonder connecting into the one true network will be able to solve privacy, scalability, extensibility, authentication, consensus, and network establishment (among a few other needs) for all the ecosystems for all time. Because it is the binary of wonder, it will provide for all base needs including gated (or ungated) access to static content, gated (or ungated) access to various applications states, and an ability to communicate with a range of ecosystem participants in a coherent and consistent manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idea two takes the opposite perspective. That there can be no binary which can, to a sufficient degree of both standardization as well as flexibility, truly meet the divergent needs that ecosystem application makers actually have. This is, again for lack of a better metaphor, the linux style of ecosystem applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us who fall squarely in camp two, we feel that ecosystem application makers can greatly benefit from increased modularity along with increased standardization around &lt;em&gt;how the modules fit together&lt;/em&gt;. Something we&amp;rsquo;ve talked about at a more technical level &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.erisindustries.com/blockchains/2015/12/31/on-blockchain-clients-in-2016/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/business/2016/04/03/wtf-is-eris/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our view focusing standardization efforts not at the point of what a single binary built to operate a single network can do, but rather on standardizing the way in which various, flexible components can talk to one another, is what will really empower progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/ecosystems_2.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, progress toward what? What do these things actually look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-an-ecosystem-application-look-like&#34;&gt;What Does an Ecosystem Application Look Like?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It depends. But hopefully it looks and feels like a &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; application, in whatever context the ecosystem application is being deployed. The advantage of leverging distributed systems technology to build ecosystem applications is that while the backends are very different than &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; applications, we ideally want the front ends (what the users of the application, well, use) to feel no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to do this, however, we need to solve a whole range of problems around distribution of standard components which are deployable on as wide a variety of hardware and operating system configurations as is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are going to bring machines properly into being first class participants in our ecosystem applications we need to expand beyond simply supporting the &amp;ldquo;big 3&amp;rdquo; OS&amp;rsquo;s. We also need to make it quick and easy for users to start and stop these complex applications in a consistent manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, why &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt; leverages docker under the hood to make the application user&amp;rsquo;s perspective as seamless as possible and to take out many of the edge cases when building for a wide range of OS and hardware combinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/ecosystems_1.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-we-go-about-building-ecosystem-applications&#34;&gt;How Do We Go About Building Ecosystem Applications?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of my thinking in this area was refined from observing ecosystems evolve during my time doing international development work, including tons of reading and thinking about how to change and evolve complex social systems within the context of fragile and/or failed states. Study of the human factors of combat and lots of insurgency theory didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt. Studying the hippies and beatniks didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the biggest step in my thinking here came from Kevin Kelly&amp;rsquo;s Out of Control; a book sent to me by a friend a few months after we started our company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lesson-1-ordering-matters&#34;&gt;Lesson 1: Ordering matters.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building ecosystem applications, it matters the order in which you go about formulating the ecosystem. Since we&amp;rsquo;re building applications humans will, at some remove, interact with, then the ordering matters on both a technical level as well as on an interaction level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you need to have enough code to get a sufficient amount of capital interested to then take the code and implementation of the various aspects of that ecosystem to the next phase. This needs to be done in concert with an actor within a given domain who has some ability to &amp;ldquo;convene&amp;rdquo; participants. Then you need to continue having a conversation and negotiation with the market both in terms of revenue and capital. Again, in concert with an entity who has &amp;ldquo;convening power&amp;rdquo;. This is much more like gardening than it is like manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what code should one focus on at first? We would argue that some level of interactivity in order to show what the backend can do, along with some idea of the backend architecture, some idea of what the business logic looks like, and a great story to tell are the proper combination to have when doing the initial move from code to capital. This is not really any different, indeed its basically the same thing, as fund raising from VC&amp;rsquo;s. Only when building an ecosystem application often you won&amp;rsquo;t be raising from a traditional VC structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first conversation with the market that raises money sufficient for the ecosystem application builders to move beyond MVP stage, then the real fun begins. At this point the technical development usually will split into four tracks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;track one&lt;/code&gt;: business logic refinement,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;track two&lt;/code&gt;: network logic refinement,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;track three&lt;/code&gt;: plugging into the rest of the things, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;track four&lt;/code&gt;: interaction logic refinement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly the non-technical side will now likely split into two different tracks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;track one&lt;/code&gt;: governance over the ecosystem application (more on governance later), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;track two&lt;/code&gt;: increasing the &amp;ldquo;convened&amp;rdquo; participants one concentric ring in the circle outward from the original few &amp;ldquo;conveners&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once those tracks finish their first major series of work and &amp;ldquo;go live&amp;rdquo; happens, and the thing runs and is increasing in value, then it either continues to do its thing by evolving and/or it goes back to the capital market for &amp;ldquo;scaling capacity&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the point here? The point is that building an ecosystem is a lot like building a business. But the target participants are often very different than those involved in building a traditional business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lesson-2-destruction-matters&#34;&gt;Lesson 2: Destruction matters.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every large change which happens in business, society, politics, or, frankly, any complex system, there will need to be some destruction of the old in order to make room for the new. This is uncontroversial, and we generally call it &lt;code&gt;creative destruction&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, simple destruction does not an ecosystem make. Usually wanton destruction makes for wastelands. This is one of the key lessons I learned from a story told in Kelly&amp;rsquo;s Out of Control. In that book, Kelly details a group who was trying to &amp;ldquo;bring back the prairies&amp;rdquo; in the midwest of the United States. The scientists knew that fire was an important part of the lifecycle of prairies, but for many years their efforts were unsuccessful because of &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; they triggered the fire. They eventually learned that they needed to trigger the fire at the correct time in order for the right effects to happen within the ecosystem they were attempting to catalyze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What they learned was this. First you plant the fire resistant plants and make sure they are hearty. Then you burn the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecosystem application makers would be wise to learn from this. That which will be destroyed when ecosystem applications come online include massive swathes of back office personnel who currently are responsible for ensuring that the enterprise&amp;rsquo;s generation 1 process automation tooling is kept in sync with other ecosystem participant enterprises&amp;rsquo; generation 1 process automation tooling. Yes, in many large organizations this is still a human driven process. But also, and probably later, existing processes within various markets will be provided with an opportunity to run more efficiently within ecosystem applications than they currently are able to run in a silo&amp;rsquo;ed environment under the control of one participant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those involved in building ecosystem applications need to have a relatively sophisticated understanding of the timing around when would be appropriate within the adoption curve of our technology to start triggering the various fires which will be a necessary, if perhaps ugly, portion of the overall creative destruction process that is constantly happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lesson-3-governance-matters-a-lot&#34;&gt;Lesson 3: Governance matters. A Lot.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My prior life involved doing governance reform work. As such, a lot of what I had to do to be successful, was to act as a convening body around various problems which needed to have some consensus as to what the response was going to be. But I had to do this with politicians which is always tricky because of the second and third level effects in which political systems operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the first development worker to expressly use budget I sort-of controlled to fund consensus activities with the Upper House of the Somaliland parliament. This was the &amp;ldquo;House of Elders&amp;rdquo;; a clan nominated, almost exclusively old men actor within the complex Somaliland governance ecosystem. Given that we (development workers) were supposed to be there (Somaliland) promoting democracy &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; governance (note the ordering), it had been frowned upon to work with the upper house due to the fact that it was an appointed rather than elected body. Yet it was one of the most powerful actors within the ecosystem; often acting as the level-headed ballast within the system as the &amp;ldquo;younger hotheads&amp;rdquo; in the &amp;ldquo;political class&amp;rdquo; did what they do in the Presidency and the lower house of parliament. For me it was a no brainer that I would be much more effective at my job if I worked with them to help them overcome some of the big problems in Somaliland. Problems that, eventually, were going to require their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the least of these, was that the Constitutional powers of the Upper House were quite ambiguous. And without a sufficiently strong judiciary to act as a counterbalance on the fundamental questions of constitutional law (namely, and I&amp;rsquo;m channeling my Constitutional Law professor here: &lt;code&gt;who decides who decides&lt;/code&gt;), the Upper House was in an awkward position to have the most (or least, depending on who you asked) power in defining their own future within a more mature Somaliland governance ecosystem. Less cryptically, the Upper House needed to decide if it would be elected (as the Constitution said they should be) or remain an appointed body (as the society had, for the most part, accepted).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked with the Chairman of the Upper House and I said I was interested in facilitating a discussion here by providing background research on the key decision points that Upper Houses typically need to make and in convening a sufficiently powerful caucus of members of his House to begin achieving consensus on what the answers to those decision points would be. Indeed, this model is how I generally operated. Help to define what the decision points are via pulling lessons from other systems based on a comparative and distillation process (which should sound familiar if you&amp;rsquo;ve heard me talk about how we do &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/CaseyKuhlman/legal-engineering&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;legal engineering&lt;/a&gt;), and then to facilitate discussion amongst the key stakeholders within various systems so that they can come up with their first answers to those questions. After that the &amp;ldquo;campaign&amp;rdquo; was generally handed off for execution by other folks who had a different focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing the research and facilitating our first few sessions with the caucus, I expressed some concern to one member of my team. I was concerned that we were spending an inordinate amount of time &amp;ldquo;talking about how we were gonna talk&amp;rdquo; and not enough time &amp;ldquo;just talking&amp;rdquo;. My team member told me that it was fine; that this is the way that things were done; and that I needed to learn a bit more patience. So I bit my tongue. It took a few more sessions to get the process questions out of the way. But once those processes of discussion were settled upon; and the agenda to discuss was settled; then, and only then, the discussion flowed. (Unfortunately at least during my tenure, it never reached sufficient consensus.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I tell that story? Because it is a lesson which ecosystem builders should take to heart. That building governance mechanisms is complex, but it is doable if one understands the context well, learns from what came before, and sufficiently outlines a path to evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-next-for-ecosystem-application-builders-and-users&#34;&gt;What is Next for Ecosystem Application Builders and Users?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/frenchy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Photo credit 1: CC-BY: francois schnell @ Flickr )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/dandeluca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Photo credit 2: CC-BY: Dan DeLuca @ Flickr )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/16210667@N02/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Photo credit 3: CC-BY-ND: Craig Sunter @ Flickr )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Marmot Video Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/05/27/international/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/05/27/international/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See, if we said &amp;ldquo;Zach does a walkthrough of Eris-cli on YouTube&amp;rdquo; you might not have clicked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you did click. And we are happy marmots for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. See below for a walkthrough on YouTube. As promised. If youv&amp;rsquo;e got any questions, hit us up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eris_ltd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S7uXHD2KgtU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Entity Global Ledger - How to liberate public data (with chains)</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/04/08/lei-global-ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/04/08/lei-global-ledger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of the key aspects of Blockchain / Distributed Ledger (DL) Technology is the ability to merge public key authentication of information with a resilient, distributed database. In this piece, which outlines an application Eris is building, I talk about this idea in greater detail using publicly available data from the Legal Entity Identifier (LEI) initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no shortage of news, blog posts, and whitepapers foreshadowing the disruption of entire industries by &lt;em&gt;blockchains&lt;/em&gt; and describing a myriad of potential use cases that will run more efficiently on a decentralized architecture. What is striking is that almost all prominently discussed topics focus on processes and scenarios with a fair amount of complexity and/or attempt to replace very established procedures. At first, this seems logical since the potential for efficiency gains usually increases with the complexity of the use case, but it seems we&amp;rsquo;re rushing too far ahead and have forgotten about one fundamental formula that has always proven helpful when venturing into new territory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Start small, learn what works and what doesn&#39;t, and build up from there
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at Eris Industries are very much about &amp;ldquo;less talking, more doing&amp;rdquo; as subscribers to our blogs and Twitter account can surely attest. So, in this article I would like to hone in on a &amp;lsquo;real world&amp;rsquo; use case that exemplifies what can be done with blockchains &lt;strong&gt;today&lt;/strong&gt;.
It is very understandable that people may feel they should wait and gain more experience and confidence with this fairly new technology before investing much effort into it. Even when investments (usually in the form of POCs or in-house / consortia experimentation) are made, many might hesitate to build and deploy &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; solutions on shared ledgers until potentially a &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;winner&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; emerges, be that a blockchain design or a common industry platform. However, I would like to show here that the technological components are mature enough, especially in Open Source, to extract value and start building &lt;strong&gt;now&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Transformational ROI from blockchain for corporates will take a good number of years. Smaller bits of ROI can be achieved tomorrow if you have the right buy in and strategy and partners.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sytaylor.net/2015/11/21/10-things-you-should-know-about-blockchains&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Simon Taylor, Nov. 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When carefully selecting use cases, opportunity opens up to implement something &lt;strong&gt;beyond POCs&lt;/strong&gt; that contributes to the learning experience at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Blockchains are a new type of hammer that can hit new nails. We don’t fully understand what the new nails look like yet, so let’s keep hitting old nails until we understand the new hammer. So it makes sense to apply this technology to well understood problems, even if they can be solved using existing technology.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitsonblocks.net/2016/04/04/what-you-get-for-free-with-blockchains/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Antony Lewis, April 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains by design come with a set of features that is desirable in most (enterprise) applications, even if it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;merely&lt;/em&gt; to reduce operational expenses for hosting, failover, or disaster recovery. The availability of blockchain platforms and toolkits further reduces costs of building custom solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, shall we dive into a discovery and selection process of what we should build?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, in order to increase the chances of arriving at a level of production-readiness let&amp;rsquo;s avoid any of the big &lt;em&gt;unresolved&lt;/em&gt; challenges of blockchains/DLT, namely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Transaction Volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidential Transactions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End-User Identity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the number of participants profiting from a blockchain solution should be as high as possible, after all it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;shared&lt;/em&gt; ledger. As detailed by Gideon Greenspan in articles from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multichain.com/blog/2015/10/private-blockchains-shared-databases&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;October&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/avoiding-pointless-blockchain-project-gideon-greenspan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;November&lt;/a&gt; of last year, blockchain technology as a shared writable data store has private as well as public utility, but the &lt;strong&gt;public domain&lt;/strong&gt; should be considered as a category that trumps most other checkpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, to be mindful of the &lt;em&gt;start small, build up&lt;/em&gt; mantra it should be our goal to identify a simple use case upon which more complex scenarios can be built. This means we&amp;rsquo;re looking for low complexity in the &lt;code&gt;business processes at a network level&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. a small number of interactions between disparate entities in a low-trust environment, yet delivering value through the shared content. Two pillars underpinning many higher level business processes are &lt;strong&gt;Master Data Management&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Reference Data Management&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado &amp;hellip; meet the candidate to be &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;ledgerized&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-legal-entity-identifier-lei&#34;&gt;The Legal Entity Identifier (LEI)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;LEI data is freely available, easy to access, without restrictions on redistribution or licensing. [&amp;hellip;] Future phases will require a new &amp;lsquo;utility strength&amp;rsquo; global infrastructure, which will have similar robustness, reliability, and business continuity capabilities as other financial market infrastructures, such as securities settlement systems and trade repositories.&amp;rdquo;
From the original &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sifma.org/uploadedfiles/issues/technology_and_operations/legal_entity_identifier/lei-preliminary-scope-plan.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2012 scope plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LEI initiative emerged out of a request by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.g20.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;G20&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FSB&lt;/a&gt; in 2011 to establish a globally unique identifier for legal entities, primarily to increase transparency of their involvement in global financial transactions (something that could&amp;rsquo;ve doubtlessly been of value when sifting through the mess of a global meltdown of the financial system, but let&amp;rsquo;s not get into that &amp;hellip;).
The LEI system as it exists today operates in three tiers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Legal Entity Identifier Regulatory Oversight Committee (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leiroc.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LEI ROC&lt;/a&gt;), comprised of more than 50 regulatory institutions worldwide and a variety of public sector stakeholders, monitors the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Global Legal Entity Identifier Foundation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gleif.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GLEIF&lt;/a&gt;) is in charge of governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Operating Units (LOUs) are accredited agencies that function as the beachhead in local jurisdictions / countries to render services around the LEI, e.g. issuing LEIs to local businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briefly a few facts about the LEI system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is an LOU&amp;rsquo;s primary responsibility to certify that the information about a company (legal name, registered address, headquarters address, entity status, etc.) is valid and current. To do so it sometimes relies on services of third-party companies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.avoxdata.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Avox&lt;/a&gt; (a subsidiary of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dtcc.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DTCC&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gmeiutility.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GMEI Utility&lt;/a&gt; operated by the DTCC in collaboration with SWIFT is by far the largest such LOU in terms of issued LEIs (see diagram below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An LEI record possesses a lifecycle that goes through different state changes (active|not_active, current|not_current, etc.) and also expires if not renewed. This lifecycle is supported by a simple business process / workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LOUs, third-party verifiers, and legal entities themselves participate in this workflow. For example, a company can register, update, or dispute their own data (which still requires verification or approval by the LOU) or request the LOU to do so on their behalf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The LEI format is based on ISO Standard 17442 and follows Financial Stability Board (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FSB&lt;/a&gt;) specifications. The LEI consists of a 20-digit alphanumeric code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/LEI-Issuer-Statistics-GLEIF.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}
&lt;div style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center&#34;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gleif.org/en/lei-data/global-lei-index/lei-statistics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.gleif.org/en/lei-data/global-lei-index/lei-statistics&lt;/a&gt;, 28-Mar-2016&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the certified issuance agencies (LOUs) in the above list owns, runs, and maintains its own infrastructure (servers, web application, and centralized database) to offer LEI issuance and search capabilities. The delta of changes at an individual local agency is uploaded and consolidated into the global &amp;ldquo;golden copy&amp;rdquo; that is managed by the GLEIF as depicted in the following diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/LEI-current.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of running and maintaining the LEI infrastructure is probably not very high compared to solutions with higher transactional volume. The individual LOUs cover parts of their costs by charging fees for registration and other maintenance transactions. As of this writing the combined fees for registering a new LEI are approximately $220 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LEI system went live in 2014, the same year &lt;code&gt;blockchain&lt;/code&gt; as a general concept separated from Bitcoin and entered the spotlight. It is an intriguing thought experiment - now that the capabilities of blockchains are more widely discussed - what this system would look like had it been implemented on a distributed, participatory architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s look at this scenario in more detail and examine the stages of implementing the LEI system as a global shared ledger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lei-global-ledger&#34;&gt;The LEI Global Ledger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its early days, Eris Industries has been advocating the utility of a blockchain as a &lt;strong&gt;data management tool&lt;/strong&gt; with unique properties: It stores both its &lt;code&gt;state &amp;amp; transition logic&lt;/code&gt; (simply put, it houses the data records including the rules that govern them, i.e. authority to access and change as well as the legality of changes). Furthermore, a blockchain distinguishes itself from previously known distributed database approaches by not having a central owner or administrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain therefore allows us to store and share a single version of the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; about the state of all LEI data as well as encode and enforce the validity of changes to this data via smart contract logic. All while the infrastructure is jointly operated by its network participants.
&lt;a name=&#34;permissioned&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;permissioned-blockchains-and-ownership&#34;&gt;Permissioned blockchains and ownership&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point it is important to take a detour and explain why this particular use case requires what is known as a &lt;em&gt;permissioned&lt;/em&gt; blockchain which necessarily introduces a level of control and ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control&lt;/strong&gt; is expressed in the permissioning layer which authorizes peers to connect to the network in different roles. For example, the group of peers responsible for validating transactions and coming to consensus on the global state of the system should be configurable as a white list of known actors. The same applies to the peers specifically allowed to commit changes to the ledger; every node on the network with &amp;lsquo;write access&amp;rsquo; to the ledger needs to be identifiable and associated with a known participant, for example, a local issuing agency (LOU). However, due to the public nature of the data, read access should not be restricted at all and anyone should be allowed to connect a &amp;lsquo;read-only&amp;rsquo; peer. This approach of &lt;code&gt;permissioned &#39;write&#39; and public &#39;read&#39;&lt;/code&gt; is sometimes also referred to as &lt;em&gt;hybrid&lt;/em&gt; blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ownership&lt;/strong&gt; needs to be established in the form of a trusted entity to:
a) guarantee the availability of the network, e.g. by running the minimum number of nodes required to keep the system available
b) function as the trusted custodian of the smart contract logic (including versioning and updates) and provide legal liability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is likely that many shared ledger solutions, especially the ones touching upon the public domain, are going to require a certain form of centralized control to maintain and version the ledger software itself as well as the smart contract code running on it. For different use cases one can imagine non-profit or publicly funded organizations, governments, municipalities, etc. to assume such responsibilities in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the financial realm there already are a number of organizations that are well positioned to fulfill the role of becoming future shepherds of decentralized, distributed infrastructure and the programs running on this infrastructure: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FSB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sifma.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SIFMA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.isda.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ISDA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dtcc.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DTCC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swift.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SWIFT&lt;/a&gt; &amp;hellip; to name a few.
Other sectors, such as healthcare, have similar umbrella organizations and for many other use cases that are going to be identified as potential distributed, shared ledger applications the local or federal government might be the default candidate to play the role of the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;trusted custodian&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Or will we create &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decentralized_autonomous_organization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DAO&lt;/a&gt;s for this? If Bitcoin has taught us one thing: Creating a blockchain protocol appears to be easier than governing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his 2015 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/wmougayar/blockchain-2015-analyzing-the-blockchain-in-financial-services&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; William Mougayar stated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Blockchain and old constructs, such as clearing houses and private exchange networks (SWIFT, CCP, FIX, DTCC) are like oil and water: they will not mix well because one is based on centrally trusted intermediaries, and the other is based on ‘no’ intermediaries and peer-to-peer trust.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With reference to the points made above, I respectfully beg to differ and recent publications appear to confirm that organizations like the DTCC are beginning to open up to the exact same ideas outlined in this article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;DTCC’s viewpoint is that basic industry master data is an ideal candidate for improvement using decentralized consensus, rule standardization and auditable change history. This information is used by the entire industry by definition, and the lack of consistency and quality is a recurrent industry problem. Further, this could be constructed in such a manner that multiple firms can be authorized as data submitters, there can be many data validators and the majority of users will be data consumers.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dtcc.com/~/media/Files/PDFs/DTCC-Embracing-Disruption.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DTCC&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Embracing Disruption&amp;rsquo;, Jan. 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get back to the LEI ledger implementation &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;architecture-overview&#34;&gt;Architecture Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diagram below outlines the components of a single peer node of such a network built using the Eris Platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/LEI-Node-Architecture.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/business/2016/04/03/wtf-is-eris/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eris Platform&lt;/a&gt; is a free and open source (FOSS) platform that facilitates building, testing, and running smart contract applications. It supports the notion of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.erisindustries.com/tutorials/advanced/services-making/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;service&lt;/a&gt; as a single module that can be started, stopped, and monitored easily. The LEI application and the parts comprising a peer node participating in the LEI Global Ledger network are wrapped inside such a service.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://erisindustries.com/components/erisdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eris:DB&lt;/a&gt; is the permissioned blockchain implementation (see &lt;a href=&#34;#permissioned&#34;&gt;Permissioned Blockchains&lt;/a&gt; above) based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ethereum.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; Virtual Machine for smart contract execution and &lt;a href=&#34;http://tendermint.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tendermint&lt;/a&gt; for efficient, non-forking &lt;a href=&#34;http://tendermint.com/posts/tendermint-vs-pbft/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PBFT&lt;/a&gt; consensus. The application consists of a number of service modules facilitating the interaction with the LEI blockchain, i.e. providing access to data on the chain as well as allowing the application to react to events in the network. Furthermore, a distributed data store is used to redundantly store the entire legal entity record. Note that the smart contract only contains the LEI itself, the data fields used in the smart contract logic, as well as the reference hash to the stored record. All legal entity data is also kept in a traditional database that functions as a cache and is kept in sync with the state registered in the blockchain. This supports the ability to index and search the content.
Essentially, this application (in its intended final state) would behave the same way and provide the same services as the GLEIF&amp;rsquo;s global search capacity combined with an LOU&amp;rsquo;s registration and maintenance capability (if the peer owner has been permissioned with a write access role!), but running distributed on all nodes of the network instead of a centralized server. &amp;hellip; Good bye backups, fail-over, and disaster recovery! You&amp;rsquo;re welcome DevOps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following sections outline the stages that can enhance and eventually transform the existing LEI system to a distributed ledger. Stages 1-3 are designed to be completely non-disruptive to the current LEI system. During these stages the LEI Global Ledger is operated in parallel to the existing infrastructure with increasing effort and inclusion of participants. This allows interested parties to share in the experience of a live blockchain application with real data; all with a minimal investment and no risk. Stage 4 (and beyond) requires definite buy-in and sponsorship by the stakeholders of the LEI eco-system due to the declared intention to eventually replace the current centralized infrastructure with a distributed, blockchain-based one.
&lt;a name=&#34;stage1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stage-1&#34;&gt;Stage 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global LEI data is freely available for download and an update is published daily. In this first stage there is no buy-in or support from any participant in the existing system. Eris Industries is responsible for downloading the daily updates and cryptographically signing the transactions that push these updates into the LEI ledger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/LEI-Net-Phase-1.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immediate effect for any consumer operating a &amp;lsquo;read-only&amp;rsquo; peer is that access to LEI data is changed from a &lt;em&gt;pull&lt;/em&gt; to a &lt;em&gt;push&lt;/em&gt; mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stage has been implemented by Eris Industries! Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;#getinvolved&#34;&gt;end of the article&lt;/a&gt; for instructions how to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stage-2&#34;&gt;Stage 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In stage 2 an entity with authorized access to the global LEI database would assume responsibility for vouching for the data veracity by signing transactions to commit updates to the ledger. The GLEIF seems to be in a perfect position to do so. The transition to this stage is as easy as hooking up a few database triggers to capture update/insert events and forward these to the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/LEI-Net-Phase-2.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stage-3&#34;&gt;Stage 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same mechanism of hooking into a database as described in stage 2 is leveraged here, but it would be the LOUs themselves that propagate data into the blockchain and the central synchronization point at the global GLEIF database can be removed. With this stage we&amp;rsquo;re closing in on the LEI ledger allowing a near real time view of the LEI records as events get reported to the ledger much closer to their points of origin. At any time the LEI ledger would provide a more accurate view of the entire system than the daily consolidated file download can provide. A beneficial side effect of the LOUs cryptographically signing their own data commits is that they become identifiable via their signatures in the ledger&amp;rsquo;s audit trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/LEI-Net-Phase-3.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stage-4&#34;&gt;Stage 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming a successful exploration and validation of the LEI ledger in stages 1-3, a blockchain-based LEI system might be deemed feasible and worthwhile considering as a full replacement of the centralized infrastructure.
However, before the latter can simply be switched off, there is some effort involved to implement and test the integration points to any centralized systems that would remain in place and now need to interact with the ledger&amp;rsquo;s API.
At the end of stage 4, all core participants of the LEI lifecycle would be fully onboarded to participate in the smart-contract-backed workflow purely through signed transactions. Known participants include all LOUs and, if applicable, third-party data verification services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/LEI-Net-Phase-4.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-stage-4&#34;&gt;Beyond Stage 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential future enhancements to the system beyond stage 4 include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legal entities participating directly in the workflow, verifying the correctness and signing off on their own data for renewal. This would require a more common and pervasive use of Public Key Infrastructure (PKI). It is not very difficult to foresee that a company having gone through a verification process to prove its identity might want to register more than the legal address in the LEI ledger, e.g. their public keys. Quite sophisticated B2B processes can be built from there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another thought experiment involves the possibility to introduce free market economic principles into the system and open up the fee collection to competition. A legal entity could simply post a registration request with a certain fee associated as a reward that can be claimed by a third party for rendering services successfully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last one is admittedly a bit far-fetched and has legal implications that cannot easily be solved with a smart contract alone (yet), so let&amp;rsquo;s leave it at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be realistic &amp;hellip; the existing LEI system works sufficiently well, so why would you even want to attempt to replace it? &amp;ldquo;Because we can&amp;rdquo; is not an answer that will convince any of the stakeholders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main motivation for writing this post was to get people that are interested in blockchains, smart contracts, and distributed applications thinking. To show what&amp;rsquo;s possible and that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait years to build something meaningful, something that provides value to a large audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I was able to demonstrate the viability of transforming an existing system like the LEI from a number of loosely joined, centralized data islands to a shared distributed ledger / smart contract application. All with very minimal investment and low to no risk in the early stages. A chance for people to experience a real blockchain application first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking that there is a risk of &amp;ldquo;blockchain (or vendor) lock-in&amp;rdquo;. However, running the proposed solution side-by-side with the existing LEI system eliminates any risk (for the time being) of betting on the wrong blockchain. Even if at a later time a different blockchain implementation becomes more suitable, one of the benefits of this design is that control is introduced via trusted custodians who have the authority to perform a data migration by recommitting all historical transactions to a new ledger, albeit the original transaction timestamps would likely get replaced. Downstream systems would experience minimal to no disruption as long as a standardized data format is adhered to (e.g. the LEI system defines an XML Schema specification).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the benefits of maintaining a globally unique registry, like the LEI, on a shared distributed ledger as a single source of truth can be proven and established, then it is not difficult to repeat the same for data with similar characteristics, e.g. the &lt;em&gt;Unique Product Identifier&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.isda.org/functional-areas/technology-infrastructure/data-and-reporting/identifiers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UPI&lt;/a&gt;). The success of such initiatives would unlock more sophisticated use cases that require a deeper involvement of existing market participants: how about *&lt;strong&gt;Corporate Actions* reporting and validation&lt;/strong&gt; on a shared ledger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verifiable public data in a trusted, distributed, participatory infrastructure can foster open innovation and unlock future use cases. Replacing existing (centrally run and controlled) services with distributed, community-supported ones would allow public, private, and especially governmental institutions to &amp;ldquo;outsorce&amp;rdquo; IT infrastructure to their own communities or citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where individuals, businesses and governments are constantly locked in a battle against bugs, fraud and malicious actors, blockchains propose an alternative. […] The paradigm shift blockchains represent can offer true data integrity, advanced digital identity systems and a new way for business to offer transparency for audit alongside access for third parties.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.information-age.com/technology/security/123460713/how-blockchains-are-redefining-cyber-security&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ben Rossi, Dec. 2015&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name=&#34;getinvolved&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember&lt;/strong&gt;: Eris Industries already built the LEI Global Ledger as depicted in the &lt;a href=&#34;#stage1&#34;&gt;Stage 1 diagram&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;re intending to voluntarily run this network for the time being, so that others get a chance to experience what a distributed, smart-contract-enabled solution feels like.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in this use case and its implementation, e.g. if you&amp;rsquo;d like to experiment with a read-only peer node or want to develop a business case out of this solution, please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact Eris Industries via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@erisindustries.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or Twitter handle &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eris_ltd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@eris_ltd&lt;/a&gt;. Please voice your opinion (good or bad) and feedback on this article by tweeting it with the hashtag &lt;code&gt;#leiledger&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to collect requests by interested parties and intend to make the &lt;code&gt;LEI Net Service&lt;/code&gt; available as part of one of the next Eris platform releases.
The smart contracts controlling the LEI lifecycle and workflow can be used as the basis to implement similar data repositories. They are being made available to subscribers of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://erisindustries.com/products/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eris Contracts Library&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: smaller;&#34;&gt;Disclaimer: Diagram graphics by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timothymorgan/sets/1615269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Timothy Morgan&lt;/a&gt; redistributed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CC License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Eris? 2016 Edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/04/03/wtf-is-eris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/04/03/wtf-is-eris/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get real. The collective data and process management space (or, as some call it, the &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; space) (or, as others may call it, the &amp;ldquo;smart contract&amp;rdquo; space), is an emerging market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it an immense pleasure to be a part of. There is an undeniable groundswell of interest in this idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that we can work to automate business processes at a network level;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that we can build applications that &lt;strong&gt;are&lt;/strong&gt; the network; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that we can bring the management of our data driven relationships (with the world, with peers, with competitors, with customers, with suppliers, etc.) into a collective, efficient space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This groundswell of interest is happening because the &lt;code&gt;idea&lt;/code&gt; is incredibly appealing. And it is appealing for some very clear groups for some very clear reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a fundamental equation which must be fulfilled here: &lt;code&gt;ideas != applications&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this market emerges, and matures, there will be changes in who is winning at any one time and there will be fluctuations around who solves which problem better. We have already started to see this take place within the enterprise applications of smart contract technology where relationships and reputations are currently being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;In the next two years, an intrepid few will have their careers made. Or lost. Or modestly altered. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/smartcontracts?src=hash&#34;&gt;#smartcontracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Casey Kuhlman (@compleatang) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/compleatang/status/675736072861696000&#34;&gt;December 12, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is probably very clear to most market participants, whether that market is called &amp;ldquo;blockchains&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;collective process management solutions&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;smart contracts&amp;rdquo; (a semantic argument better left to the twitter-rena and other such upstanding locales), is that there are currently &lt;strong&gt;a lot of ways&lt;/strong&gt; to skin any one cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are working on chains right now, and you are in the business of consuming upstream, you have a lot of choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer in a bitcoin + webapp company what&amp;rsquo;s your mix of nodes between the competing options? (Well, not today because the Chinese miners &amp;ldquo;made a statement&amp;rdquo;, but you know, yesterday?) (Also, what&amp;rsquo;s it gonna be tomorrow when the winds of change blow in a different direction&amp;hellip; potentially?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer in a blockchain startup who sees a gap in which you can provide value, but you need to quickly and easily refine your value proposition; do you have a mechanism for trying out a Ripple payments layer matched to a merkle tree thing anchored into bitcoin? (Well, not today because the investors really would like more of a focus on bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s blockchain?) (Wait, what&amp;rsquo;s gonna happen tomorrow when ether rises another 20%? :moon:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer within a financial services company tasked with a now massive influx of high level interest. You know, folks came back from the conferences all &amp;ldquo;blockchain-ed&amp;rdquo;. If you&amp;rsquo;re in that human&amp;rsquo;s shoes how are you supposed to choose on what to build? There&amp;rsquo;s smart contract chains and tokenized chains? There&amp;rsquo;s hosted chains with APIs, and there&amp;rsquo;s managed chains, and there&amp;rsquo;s build my own chains? Reading blogs and whitepapers may be part of your job, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t just get to building the PoC you&amp;rsquo;ll spend your whole contract just evaluating options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This complexity and competition leads directly to what eris &lt;strong&gt;actually is&lt;/strong&gt;, which in many cases is different than what folks &lt;strong&gt;think it is&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;eris-the-vision&#34;&gt;Eris: The Vision&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given all the above we have three focusing streams for designing what we build at eris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belief 1&lt;/strong&gt;: We are entering a world of a plurality of chains, a plurality of smart contract networks, and a plurality of applications which leverage that ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belief 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Tooling matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belief 3&lt;/strong&gt;: The value that our tech can provide is in automating business processes at a network level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the design and architecture and most of the reason that eris is built the way that it is, is a reflection of the above vision; which has been developed and refined during two years of building some of the most advanced cross-system distributed applications around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;eris-architecture-that-embraces-plurality&#34;&gt;Eris: Architecture That Embraces Plurality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt; let&amp;rsquo;s look at what a blockchain application &amp;ldquo;actually&amp;rdquo; is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-services.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that for any single application some of the pieces may be &amp;ldquo;n/a&amp;rdquo; and the arrows connecting components may work drastically different than in the diagram. The diagram isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to cover the entire field of options, nor any one specific application. But for most of the applications, most of the time it will suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much every blockchain application we know can fit somewhere in this framework (even if spread across hardware and does not use docker). Many bitcoin based web apps can easily fit in this paradigm (with the proviso at the top), most ethereum based apps can easily fit in this paradigm (with the proviso at the top), and most &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/code&gt; based apps can easily fit in this paradigm (with the proviso at the top) (more on &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/code&gt; in a moment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, though, becomes: how can the application&amp;rsquo;s users (not to mention developers and contributors interesting in helping) get started?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the community there have been basically three answers to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run everything through traditional webapps and connect the chains as microservices;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run all the things on a single blockchain (by which I mean the one I fancy most&amp;hellip; today); or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use docker and some nice abstractions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, our marmot-y answer is clearly in the camp of Number 3. Why? Because when application builders build using a paradigm such as ours, they get to build their applications on a rich fabric of modules which work together to varying degrees based on a variety of factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-options.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This architecture allows eris to embrace a wide variety of developer needs. But it really begins to shine when more &lt;code&gt;super users&lt;/code&gt; are given access to help validate and operate smart contract and blockchain backed applications. Thanks to innovative leaders like many of the &amp;ldquo;Ðapps&amp;rdquo; crowd, as well as others, such as OpenBazaar building on bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s backbone, more and more users will have access to run their blockchain applications wherever they want. This is exciting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is eris? It&amp;rsquo;s a blockchain application platform that makes it easy to build, test, and use your blockchain applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While exciting, it also places a fairly large load on a super user to compile, install, configure, etc. all the components and pieces that their applications use. Let&amp;rsquo;s just assume a given &lt;code&gt;super user&lt;/code&gt; wants to run OpenBazaar and a single Geth-IPFS Ðapp. What would be necessary to go from zero to &amp;ldquo;running&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;openbazaar&#34;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, their installation instructions are pretty clean! (Well done!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Client:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-openbazaar1.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-openbazaar2.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not bad. Wanna get started with openbazaar on eris?&lt;/p&gt;
eris services start openbazaar

&lt;h3 id=&#34;geth-ipfs-ðapp&#34;&gt;Geth-IPFS Ðapp&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, both of these are easily installed via binaries! (Well done!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IPFS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-ipfs.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-geth.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super clean install paths for both. Obviously, both being go based components, users can be easily build them from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wanna get started with geth-ipfs on eris?&lt;/p&gt;
eris services start ipfs geth

&lt;p&gt;Multiply that effort across the range of possible components which the emerging plurality of chains, smart contract networks, file systems, and applications will leverage and it should be clear why eris is architected in the way that we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we say that &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt; is a blockchain application platform, this is what we mean. We&amp;rsquo;re making the thing that you can use to make it easy to build, test, and run your blockchain things. No matter the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-apps.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see a full list of the services eris is capable of running out of the box &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eris-ltd/eris-services&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;please see our repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt; leverages docker under the hood, &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt; can run (nearly) anywhere via direct install, or even just speaking to a remote docker engine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-remotes.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;eris-runtime&#34;&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have long been leaders in the permissioned smart contract network space. From our early explorations with &lt;code&gt;thelonious&lt;/code&gt; to our latter explorations which led to &lt;code&gt;eris:db&lt;/code&gt; (as well as significant contributions to the previous major version of the tendermint code base), we have understood that automating data driven relationships on a &amp;ldquo;less than global&amp;rdquo; basis was going to be crucial for the success of this technology within industry. &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/code&gt; is the next evolution of our efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above framework pictures, in particular this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-options.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reference a component of eris which is currently not in our repositories (&lt;code&gt;eris-rt-XXX&lt;/code&gt; in the above). The components in the above image that are colored green are areas where eris is intending to keep building. This is not a &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.erisindustries.com/blockchains/2015/12/31/on-blockchain-clients-in-2016/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;big departure&lt;/a&gt; for us. Indeed, it is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/philosophy/2016/03/02/eris-and-tendermint/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;continuation of a path&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;rsquo;ve been heading for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what exactly, is &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/code&gt;? Over the next few release cycles (leading up to our 1.0 release) we will be refactoring our current efforts to fit more cleanly into the modular components outlined here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-rt.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/code&gt; will ensure access for blockchain application builders to the best permissionable smart contract network environment in a more modular and extensible framework. &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/code&gt; will include all of the relevant default components, wisely connected with sane defaults, besides keys and files, necessary to build a wide variety of blockchain and smart contract backed applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The runtime won&amp;rsquo;t, obviously, be for every blockchain and smart contract backed application, but after building industrial strength blockchain and smart contract backed applications for wee while now, it is what we need, the majority of the time, to continue pushing the envelope as to what this tech can do and can be used for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;eris-runtime-contracts&#34;&gt;eris:runtime:contracts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start at the top of the diagram. With the smart contracts &amp;ldquo;layer&amp;rdquo;. What does that mean? Well, to us at Eris it means:&lt;/p&gt;
cryptographically verifiable computation over cryptographically verifiable data

&lt;p&gt;While the term folks use is &amp;ldquo;smart contracts&amp;rdquo;, what we are really talking about is &amp;ldquo;deterministic computation&amp;rdquo; (or &amp;ldquo;verifiable computation&amp;rdquo;). No matter what it is called, it is what is necessary to highly automate business processes &lt;strong&gt;at the network level&lt;/strong&gt; (meaning the entire network performs the computation). The computation must be verified by many actors on the network who come to consensus as to the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; answer should there be any disagreement (or acts of god, or random errors, or malicious actors). In addition, nodes who join a network after its inception will be required to perform an audit function on the system as they &amp;ldquo;catch up&amp;rdquo; with the rest of the network; this means they have to fully verify the computation even much later in time. Which means the computation needs to be highly deterministic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This component will (very soon) begin its life as Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s VM and the applications-relevant permissions of eris:db&amp;rsquo;s current permission layer. (It&amp;rsquo;s more or less equivalent in functionality to the &amp;ldquo;top half&amp;rdquo; of the current Tendermint chain client we use, only heavily updated) &lt;code&gt;eris:db&lt;/code&gt; for the record will slowly be phased out as a term we use at eris. But the ideas of &lt;code&gt;eris:db&lt;/code&gt;, like the ideas of &lt;code&gt;thelonious&lt;/code&gt; before it, will be carried forward, extended and improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime:contracts&lt;/code&gt; will talk TMSP to a Tendermint Engine, which is in the midst of its own refactor to become a more &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; consensus engine (It&amp;rsquo;s more or less equivalent in functionality to the &amp;ldquo;bottom half&amp;rdquo; of the current Tendermint chain client we use, only heavily updated). &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime:contracts&lt;/code&gt; is scheduled to be released in our 0.12.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will, over our 1.x release cycles, as more options to perform highly deterministic and verifiable computation come on line, be seeking to integrate additional options as parameters for the runtime (of course they can always be ran as eris services :-) ). But for now Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s VM is, in our experience, still the best highly deterministic interpreter on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will also, over our 1.x release cycles, as more options in the transactional and consensus engine compontent come on line, be seeking to integrate additional options as parameters for the runtime (of course they can always be ran as eris services :-) ). But for now Tendermint is, in our experience, still the most mature permissionable proof of stake consensus engine on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;eris-runtime-workers&#34;&gt;eris:runtime:workers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to needing fully verifiable computation, many applications which are automating business processes at a network level need to perform what is, fundamentally:&lt;/p&gt;
repeatable computation over unverifiable data

&lt;p&gt;In other words, this component of an application needs to be able to do &amp;ldquo;repeatable computation&amp;rdquo;. What am I talking about here? One easy example is a process that every hour makes an API call to a price feed, signs it, and send it to a chain, but there are tons of computation that need to happen in response to various events (which may be clock based events, triggers from the transactional engine, or triggers from the verifiable computation component).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I don&amp;rsquo;t like the term, due to its overuse, workers are meant to provide an easy &lt;code&gt;oracle&lt;/code&gt; framework to application makers. They are repeatable, but effectively subjective scripts which are needed to do things for your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scripts ran in this portion of the runtime are unverifiable computation because they are not highly deterministic. To that end, they are not, as we would define them, smart contracts, but they are repeatable computation. Meaning that others can also do whatever it is that is to be done (if they have access to the scripts necessary, which may or may not be gated depending on what the application designers needed). Only, in the context of &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime:workers&lt;/code&gt;, the computation that needs to be done would then be signed by a different key (depending on the node and application design) before sending the information back to the chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime:workers&lt;/code&gt; node-based framework these computations will be quite easy. This component is scheduled to be released in our 1.0.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;eris-runtime-gateway&#34;&gt;eris:runtime:gateway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;eris:db&lt;/code&gt; currently has two RPC ports. One of which talks to our low level, go-based tooling, and the other talks to our javascript tooling. These two RPCs actually are built to operate differently, but there is some overlap. The current code which is most of &lt;code&gt;eris:db&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s repository will be reconciled into a component we call &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime:gateway&lt;/code&gt;. It will provide coherent, managed routing of messages amongst the various other components of the runtime while also acting as a simple way to bring reliency and coherence to clients which need to interface with the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By maintaining a gateway which is gauranteed to interface cleanly with eris built client libraries, we can, for example, allow application designers to switch their consensus engine or verifiable computation components over time with minimal impact. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s all open source so application builder&amp;rsquo;s aren&amp;rsquo;t locked into anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This component is scheduled to be released during our 0.12.x release series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;upgrading-to-eris-runtime&#34;&gt;Upgrading to eris:runtime&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental components of the &lt;code&gt;eris:runtime&lt;/code&gt; already exist in &lt;code&gt;eris:db&lt;/code&gt; in either the repo itself or in its vendored dependencies, so the upgrade path for current users of &lt;code&gt;eris chains&lt;/code&gt; should be (mostly) seamless. Although, this is pre 1.0 software so we cannot promise that there will not be any breaking changes, we will have upgrade functionality for &lt;code&gt;eris chains&lt;/code&gt; baked into &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt; in our 0.12.0 release when the most invasive change (breaking apart the &amp;ldquo;application&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;consensus&amp;rdquo; components and connecting them over the tendermint socket protocol: TMSP) happens. This upgrade functionality will provide capability to save and import your state as you upgrade a smart contract network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remainder of the changes we will be making should be mostly transparent to users. As always, this is open source. Please feel free to pitch in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;eris-tooling-that-matters&#34;&gt;Eris: Tooling That Matters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world of a plurality of chains and smart contract networks and applications, more tooling is required for builders than simply application management tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You still need tooling capable of handling smart contract bundles if you&amp;rsquo;re going to be working with smart contract systems. Since we started this journey, &lt;a href=&#34;http://coda.caseykuhlman.com/entries/2014/introducing-ethereum-package-manager.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;now more than two years ago&lt;/a&gt;, our interest in legal engineering has forced us to build tooling to handle large systems of smart contracts, or &lt;strong&gt;Verifiable Computation Tooling&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-pkgs.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need tooling which has been built from the ground up to provide your developers and users with chain lifecycle management tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; | append:&amp;lsquo;/wtf-eris-chains.png&amp;rsquo; | img }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a range of tooling that still needs to be built, but in combination with other ecosystems, the range of tools available to application makers is increasing by the day. Which, to be clear, is a wonderful thing. If you are a tool builder looking to interface with the growing eris ecosystem give us a shout on Twitter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;eris-build-and-run-networked-based-business-process-automation-applications&#34;&gt;Eris: Build and Run Networked-Based Business Process Automation Applications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other side of &lt;code&gt;eris&lt;/code&gt; is our legal engineering side. That bit &lt;a href=&#34;https://erisindustries.com/products/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;we don&amp;rsquo;t give away&lt;/a&gt;. Oh, and to be clear, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to use our legal engineering talent &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.erisindustries.com/tutorials/solidity/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;to achieve your goals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;eris-the-bottom-line&#34;&gt;Eris: The Bottom Line&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Move faster. Move &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the flow of distributed computing. #profit&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eris Commercial Paper Bundles: Toolkit for Financial Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/31/commercial-paper-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/31/commercial-paper-intro/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;eris-commercial-paper-bundles-toolkit-for-financial-engineering&#34;&gt;Eris Commercial Paper Bundles: Toolkit for Financial Engineering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An introduction to smart contracts for the digital non-native.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hash&lt;/strong&gt;. Computers work because almost any kind of information can be transformed into a string of zeroes and ones called binary code. Once data has been reduced to binary code, computers can apply mathematical operations to it to produce reliable results. Cryptography involves passing the binary code of a piece of data through a series of arithmetic operations to produce a hash, an encoded string of letters and numbers that represents the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hashing is a one-way operation: while a certain data set will always produce the same unique identifier (the &lt;em&gt;hash&lt;/em&gt;), it is effectively impossible to do the math in reverse to decode the data from just the hash. One must have a key to access cryptographically stored information. Hashing and decentralized distributed data structures can be combined with business logic to make many kinds of applications, for example, value tokens. Value tokens, however, are just one way of using blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;. Smart contracts are cryptographically secure computational processes acting on cryptographically secure data in blockchain systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-s-the-big-deal&#34;&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s the big deal?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart contracts enable the technological evolution of existing legal concepts and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precedent&lt;/strong&gt;. Humans have long understood that history is our best guide, even when blazing new territory. Common law legal systems like the UK and US base their law, especially contract law, on &lt;em&gt;precedent&lt;/em&gt;, an earlier event that acts as a guide for subsequent similar circumstances. The collection, preservation and accessibility of legal precedent is a critical function of common law systems that will be enhanced by smart contracts that combine value creation, storage and transfer with logic and immutability of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authenticity, registries, sworn statements and real problems to solve&lt;/strong&gt;. Determining authenticity of data for the purposes of making business and judicial decisions is another critical job of legal systems. To support this, governments often establish registries that give an “official” version of authenticity for property and relationships that are of public importance. This reliable version of important facts allows for predictability and growth in commercial relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For legal proceedings, choosing what data to consider authentic when making decisions is a critical question. Historically, common law courts have relied on sworn statements of humans to establish significant facts. Large-scale failures of the current authenticity protocol for financial documents can have disastrous effects. For example, the ability to hide bad loans and produce bogus affidavits were important elements in the financial crisis of 2008. Smart contracts can both verify information in certain transactions more reliably than humans and allow a window into commerce for businesspeople and regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the promises of smart contracts is to limit the role of the middleman in commerce, reducing pain points that slow the velocity of money and retard growth. For example, legal due diligence for a simple purchase of company assets can involve checklists of information more than thirty pages long. In a mature smart contract system, these due diligence and compliance tasks may be more effectively and cheaply handled by smart contracts with access to immutable data registries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those whose job is to increase the amount of money in the financial system by creating investments, smart contracts may provide solutions to liquidity problems by reinventing the processes of trading and settlement. Freed from many drains on resources, businesses will be able to concentrate on growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big prize&lt;/strong&gt;. Smart contracts may not deliver the financial utopia many imagine, but they will deliver critical tools: increased data certainty and reliability of business processes. Data certainty means agreement as to the veracity and authenticity of evidence. It has the potential to eliminate the need to reconcile massive data systems and associated cost and delay. A cohesive approach to building such a mammoth blockchain system will require large-scale coordination across myriad sectors but is necessary to avoid a disjointed, siloed result that loses the benefits of smart contract technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;commercial-paper&#34;&gt;Commercial Paper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for commerce to flow, fungibility of value items is critical, as is careful typing and classifying of rights, obligations and objects. For a value object to function as currency, it must flow through commerce with as few strings attached as possible. Lawyers, businesspeople and governments have grappled with this issue for centuries - and one such set of tools that has evolved is &lt;em&gt;commercial paper,&lt;/em&gt; a type of debt obligation that specifically mimics the fungibility of fiat money while giving protection against adverse property claims (analogous to a cryptocurrency double-spend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial paper value is based on a promise and obligation to pay money in the future. The basic unit of commercial paper, the promissory note, may be recombined in infinite ways. The flexibility and reliability of commercial paper systems allows businesses to use these tools for growth. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/announcements/2016/03/03/r3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eris debuted commercial paper prototypes with over 40 of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest banks last month.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eris&amp;rsquo;s inaugural smart contract product, &lt;strong&gt;Eris Industries’ Commercial Paper Software Bundles,&lt;/strong&gt; combines the obligation-based building blocks of commerce with smart contract potential. The ability to create promissory notes, issue shares and keep track of assets creates the toolkit for financial engineering: out of these simple structures flow complex uses like time notes, demand notes, order paper, bearer paper, corporate bonds, securities, stocks, dividends, debentures, certificates of deposit, drafts, loan originations, repurchase agreements, mutual funds, reinsurance and equity options, to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crafted to work in multiple blockchain environments, Eris Commercial Paper Bundles deliver tools to build a strong smart contract use case system. Eris’s Commercial Paper is engineered for multidimensional applications, incorporating the lessons of history and precedent as well as the promise of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Eris Industries&amp;rsquo; Smart Contract Libraries subscriptions, please write us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@erisindustries.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;contact@erisindustries.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eris teams up with Ledger for blockchain hardware security</title>
      <link>http://localhost/2016/03/18/ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost/2016/03/18/ledger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;m cognisant that self-praise is no recommendation, at Eris Industries, we&amp;rsquo;re fast becoming the leading platform provider for enterprise blockchain applications - as evidenced by our recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/01/28/pwc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;strategic partnership with PwC&lt;/a&gt; and successful delivery of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.erisindustries.com/products/2016/01/28/pwc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;commercial paper prototype&lt;/a&gt; system for 40 of R3 CEV&amp;rsquo;s 43 member banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That market, by itself, is already too large for any single company to service. And that market will grow, not shrink, as the range of possible use-cases expands. However, rather than try to own 100% of the stack or 100% of every relationship, we at Eris Industries choose to collaborate with the best companies in the market. Yes, we could try to &amp;ldquo;do it all&amp;rdquo; and then bill a lot more. However, by teaming up, we ensure that we do the job right, the first time. And that&amp;rsquo;s the best way to turn a bank into a marmot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; properly involves rather a lot more work than forking Bitcoin and bolting a slick UI onto it. Applied cryptography is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://iang.org/papers/fc7.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dauntingly complex&lt;/a&gt; discipline; consulting, legal thinking, engineering, and integrations all need to be brought to bear on a problem at the same time if you&amp;rsquo;re going to get one of these systems really humming along. Only by picking the right friends will you be able to build the right solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One huge problem facing blockchains (and cryptosystems generally) that not many companies are grappling with well is key management and hardware security. One company, however, is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why today we&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce that we&amp;rsquo;ve selected &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ledger.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ledger&lt;/a&gt; as our hardware security partner to help protect our clients&amp;rsquo; blockchain-based infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ledger is a technological leader in the blockchain security industry and provides a wide range of trusted hardware solutions for both consumer and enterprise usage. The company put itself on the map in 2015 with its best-selling smart card-based hardware wallet, and has since extended this to the B2B market with its TEE (Trusted Execution Environment) and HSM (Hardware Security Module) solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey Kuhlman, our CEO, commented for a joint press release issued on behalf of both firms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ledger is at the forefront of providing tools to secure blockchains and manage private keys. Ledger&amp;rsquo;s BOLOS platform is a crucial security offering which fills a vital security gap in the blockchain ecosystem. We are therefore very pleased to be working with Ledger, and together we will provide our users with the most flexible, capable, and user-friendly application development tooling in the market today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Eric Larchevêque, Ledger&amp;rsquo;s CEO, has some good things to say about us too. Which is nice. He commented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Eris Industries is a fast growing blockchain infrastructure provider for Fortune 500 customers. We are looking forward to deploying our solutions to their infrastructure and bring a strong layer of security to the management of critical workflows and cryptographic primitives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, press releases are always full of partnering companies saying nice things about each other, but in this case we certainly mean every word of it. 2016 has already been full of exciting developments in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We very much look forward to working with Ledger as we see just how much more exciting it will become.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>